<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-3/article-ii/division-1/section-sec.-3.17">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Use of sound devices*—Prohibited; exceptions</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-3/article-ii/division-1/section-sec.-3.17"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 3_17">
      <num>SEC. 3.17</num>
      <heading>Use of sound devices*—Prohibited; exceptions</heading>
      <content>
        <p>No person shall use, operate or cause to be used or operated any radio, phonograph,
               loud-speaker, sound amplifier or other machine or device for the producing or reproducing
               of sound which is cast upon the public streets for the purpose of commercial advertising
               or attracting the attention of the public to any building or structure, except as
               hereinafter provided:</p>
        <p>(1)</p>
        <p>Christmas season. During the Christmas season such sound device may be used or operated for playing
                  music related to the Christmas season only in accordance with the following regulations:</p>
        <p>(a)</p>
        <p>Such sound device may be used or operated only for the period December fifth through
                  December twenty-fifth of each year;</p>
        <p>(b)</p>
        <p>Such sound device shall only be used or operated between the hours of nine a.m. and
                  ten p.m. Monday through Saturday, and shall not be used or operated on Sundays;</p>
        <p>(c)</p>
        <p>No such sound device shall be permitted within one hundred (100) yards of any hospital
                  or public library;</p>
        <p>(d)</p>
        <p>The volume of sound shall be controlled so that it will not be audible for a distance
                  in excess of one hundred fifty (150) feet from the sound device and so that the volume
                  is not unreasonably loud, raucous, jarring, disturbing or a nuisance to persons within
                  the area of audibility;</p>
        <p>(e)</p>
        <p>No such sound device shall be placed or located so as to project into or over any
                  portion of the public street or sidewalk.</p>
        <p>(2)</p>
        <p>Sound amplification permits.</p>
        <p>(a)</p>
        <p>Permit required. A permit may be issued for the use or operation of a sound device upon the approval
                  of an application as set forth herein.</p>
        <p>1.</p>
        <p>If the request for sound amplification is not connected with the closure of a public
                  or private street, thoroughfare, sidewalk or parking lot or the interference with
                  normal vehicular or pedestrian traffic, the application shall be filed with the community
                  services department and may be approved by the director. The completed application
                  shall be filed with the community services department at least ten (10) business days
                  prior to the date of the proposed use for operation.</p>
        <p>2.</p>
        <p>Sound amplification requests connected with the closure of a public or private street,
                  thoroughfare, sidewalk or parking lot or the interference with normal vehicular or
                  pedestrian traffic must be approved by the city council concurrent with any other
                  required permit. The application must be filed with the community services department
                  at least ninety (90) days prior to the date of the proposed use or operation.</p>
        <p>(b)</p>
        <p>Contents of the application. The written application for a sound amplification permit must set forth the following
                  information:</p>
        <p>1.</p>
        <p>Name and home address of each applicant.</p>
        <p>2.</p>
        <p>Address of place of business of each applicant.</p>
        <p>3.</p>
        <p>Address or address of proposed use of sound device.</p>
        <p>4.</p>
        <p>Purpose for which the sound device will be used.</p>
        <p>5.</p>
        <p>Proposed hours of operation or use of sound device.</p>
        <p>6.</p>
        <p>Number of days of proposed operation or use of device.</p>
        <p>7.</p>
        <p>A general description of the sound device to be used or operated.</p>
        <p>8.</p>
        <p>A description of the placement or location of the sound device at the place where
                  it is to be used or operated.</p>
        <p>(c)</p>
        <p>Criteria for approval. The approving body may issue a permit for the use or operation of a sound device
                  upon determining that such use or operation will not be a nuisance and will not be
                  detrimental to the public peace, comfort, safety or general welfare. Such permit shall
                  prescribe, in addition to the regulations hereinafter set forth, such reasonable conditions
                  as city council or community services director shall deem necessary to effectively
                  carry out the intent and purpose of this section.</p>
        <p>(d)</p>
        <p>The permit, or duplicate original thereof, shall be kept in the possession of some
                  responsible person at the place or places the sound device is used, during the time
                  such sound device is in use or operation. The permit shall be promptly displayed and
                  shown to any police officer of the city upon request.</p>
        <p>(e)</p>
        <p>A nonrefundable application fee as set by council resolution shall be charged to process
                  each application.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 175.499, 10/13/58; Ord. No. 1.97, 1/14/97.)</p>
        <p>* As to noises generally, see Sec. 21.27 of this code. As to sound trucks generally, see Sec. 19.20 and Sec. 21.33.</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
