<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/part-i/article-xvii/section-1705">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Just cause for eviction protections</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/part-i/article-xvii/section-1705"
             temporalId="sSection 1705">
      <num>Section 1705</num>
      <heading>Just cause for eviction protections</heading>
      <content>
        <p>(a)</p>
        <p>No Landlord shall take action to terminate any tenancy, including but not limited
               to making a demand for possession of a Rental Unit, threatening to terminate a tenancy
               orally or in writing, serving any notice to quit or other eviction notice, or bringing
               any action to recover possession, or be granted recovery of possession of a Rental
               Unit unless at least one of the following conditions exists:</p>
        <p>(1)</p>
        <p>Failure to Pay Rent. The Tenant has failed, after three days' written notice as provided by law, to pay
               the amount stated in the notice, so long as the amount stated does not exceed the
               Rent to which the Landlord is legally entitled under the Rental Housing Agreement,
               this Article, state, and any other local law.</p>
        <p>(2)</p>
        <p>Breach of Lease. The Tenant has continued, after the Landlord has served the Tenant with Written Notice
               to Cease, to substantially violate any of the material terms of the Rental Housing
               Agreement, except the obligation to surrender possession on proper notice as required
               by law, and provided that such terms are reasonable and legal and have been accepted
               in writing by the Tenant; and provided further that, where such terms have been accepted
               by the Tenant or made part of the Rental Housing Agreement subsequent to the initial
               creation of the tenancy, the Landlord shall have first notified the Tenant in writing
               that he or she need not accept such terms.</p>
        <p>(A)</p>
        <p>Notwithstanding any contrary provision in this Section, a Landlord shall not take
               any action to terminate a tenancy based on a Tenant's sublease of the Rental Unit
               if the following requirements are met:</p>
        <p>(i)</p>
        <p>The Tenant continues to reside in the Rental Unit as his, her, or their Primary Residence;</p>
        <p>(ii)</p>
        <p>The sublessee replaces one or more departed Tenants under the Rental Housing Agreement
               on a one-for-one basis; and</p>
        <p>(iii)</p>
        <p>The Landlord has unreasonably withheld the right to sublease following written request
               by the Tenant. If the Landlord fails to respond to the Tenant in writing within fourteen
               (14) days of receipt of the Tenant's written request, the Tenant's request shall be
               deemed approved by the Landlord. A Landlord's reasonable refusal of the Tenant's written
               request may not be based on the proposed additional occupant's lack of creditworthiness,
               if that person will not be legally obligated to pay some or all of the Rent to the
               Landlord. A Landlord's reasonable refusal of the Tenant's written request may be based
               on, but is not limited to, the ground that the total number of occupants in a Rental
               Unit exceeds the maximum number of occupants as determined under Section 503(b) of the Uniform Housing Code as incorporated by Health &amp; Safety Code Section 17922.</p>
        <p>(B)</p>
        <p>Protections for Families. Notwithstanding any contrary provision in this Section, a Landlord shall not take
               any action to terminate a tenancy as a result of the addition to the Rental Unit of
               a Tenant's child, parent, grandchild, grandparent, brother, or sister, or the spouse
               or domestic partner (as defined in California Family Code Section 297) of such relatives,
               or as a result of the addition of the spouse or domestic partner of a Tenant, so long
               as the number of occupants does not exceed the maximum number of occupants as determined
               under Section 503(b) of the Uniform Housing Code as incorporated by California Health &amp; Safety Code
               17922. The Committee may promulgate regulations that will further protect families
               and promote stability for school-aged children.</p>
        <p>(3)</p>
        <p>Nuisance. The Tenant has continued, after the Landlord has served the Tenant with a Written
               Notice to Cease, to commit or expressly permit a nuisance in the Rental Unit.</p>
        <p>(4)</p>
        <p>Criminal Activity. The Tenant has continued, after the Landlord has served the Tenant with a Written
               Notice to Cease, to be so disorderly as to destroy the peace, quiet, comfort, or safety
               of the Landlord or other tenants at the Property. Such disorderly conduct includes
               violations of state and federal criminal law that destroy the peace, quiet, comfort,
               or safety of the Landlord or other tenants at the Property.</p>
        <p>(5)</p>
        <p>Failure to Give Access. The Tenant has continued to refuse, after the Landlord has served the Tenant with
               a Written Notice to Cease and without good cause, to grant the Landlord reasonable
               access to the Rental Unit as required by state or local law.</p>
        <p>(6)</p>
        <p>Necessary and Substantial Repairs Requiring Temporary Vacancy. The Landlord, after having obtained all necessary permits from the City, and having
               provided written notice to the Tenant pursuant to state law, seeks in good faith to
               undertake substantial repairs that are necessary to bring the Rental Unit into compliance
               with applicable codes and laws affecting the health and safety of tenants of the building,
               provided that:</p>
        <p>(A)</p>
        <p>The repairs necessitate that the Tenant vacate the Rental Unit because the work will
               render the rental unit uninhabitable for a period of not less than thirty (30) days;</p>
        <p>(B)</p>
        <p>The Landlord gives advance notice to the Tenant of the Tenant's right to elect between:</p>
        <p>(i)</p>
        <p>The right of first refusal to any comparable vacant Rental Unit owned by the Landlord
               at the same Rent, if such comparable vacant unit exists; or</p>
        <p>(ii)</p>
        <p>The first right of return to reoccupy the unit upon completion of the repairs at the
               same Rent charged to the Tenant before the Tenant temporarily vacated the Rental Unit.</p>
        <p>(iii)</p>
        <p>In the event that the Tenant elects to accept an offer to move to a comparable vacant
               Rental Unit at the same Rent, the Tenant is not eligible for any Relocation Assistance
               pursuant to Subsection 1705(b) herein.</p>
        <p>(C)</p>
        <p>In the event the Landlord files a Petition for Individual Rent Adjustment within six
               (6) months following the completion of the work, the Tenant shall be party to such
               proceeding as if he or she were still in possession, unless the Landlord shall submit
               with such application a written waiver by the Tenant of his or her right to reoccupy
               the premises pursuant to this Subsection.</p>
        <p>(7)</p>
        <p>Owner Move-In. The Landlord seeks, after providing written notice to the Tenant pursuant to state
               law, to recover possession of the Rental Unit in good faith for use and occupancy
               as a Primary Residence by the Landlord, or the Landlord's spouse, domestic partner,
               children, parents or grandparents.</p>
        <p>(A)</p>
        <p>As used in this Subsection &quot;Landlord,&quot; shall only include a Landlord that is a natural
               person and has at least a fifty percent (50%) recorded ownership interest in the Property.</p>
        <p>(B)</p>
        <p>No eviction may take place under this Subsection if the same Landlord or enumerated
               relative already occupies a unit on the Property, or if a vacancy already exists on
               the Property. At all times a Landlord may request a reasonable accommodation if the
               Landlord or enumerated relative is Disabled and another unit in Mountain View is necessary
               to accommodate the person's disability.</p>
        <p>(C)</p>
        <p>Any notice terminating tenancy pursuant to this Subsection shall contain the name,
               address and relationship to the Landlord of the person intended to occupy the Rental
               Unit.</p>
        <p>(D)</p>
        <p>The Landlord or enumerated relative must intend in good faith to move into the Rental
               Unit within sixty (60) days after the Tenant vacates and to occupy the Rental Unit
               as a Primary Residence for at least thirty-six (36) consecutive months. The Committee
               may adopt regulations governing the determination of good faith.</p>
        <p>(E)</p>
        <p>If the Landlord or relative specified on the notice terminating tenancy fails to occupy
               the Rental Unit within sixty (60) days after the Tenant vacates, the Landlord shall:</p>
        <p>(i)</p>
        <p>Offer the Rental Unit to the Tenant who vacated it at the same Rent in effect when
               the Tenant vacated; and</p>
        <p>(ii)</p>
        <p>Pay to said Tenant all reasonable expenses incurred in moving to and from the Rental
               Unit.</p>
        <p>(F)</p>
        <p>A Landlord may not evict a Tenant pursuant to this Subsection if the Tenant (1) has
               resided in the Rental Unit for at least five (5) years and is either at least sixty-two
               (62) years old or Disabled; or (2) is certified as being terminally ill by the Tenant's
               treating physician. Notwithstanding the above, a Landlord may evict a Tenant who qualifies
               for the exemption herein if the Landlord or enumerated relative who will occupy the
               Rental Unit also meets the criteria for this exemption and no other units are available.</p>
        <p>(8)</p>
        <p>Withdrawal of the Unit Permanently from Rental Market. The Landlord seeks in good faith to recover possession to withdraw all Rental Units
               of an entire Property from the rental market. The Landlord first must have filed the
               requisite documents with the Committee initiating the procedure for withdrawing Rental
               Units from rent or lease under Government Code Section 7060 et. seq. and all regulations
               passed by the Committee, with the intention of completing the withdrawal process and
               going out of the rental business. Tenants shall be entitled to a minimum of 120-day
               notice or one (1) year in the case Tenants are defined as senior or Disabled under
               Government Code Section 12955.3. Notice times may be increased by regulations if state
               law allows for additional time.</p>
        <p>(9)</p>
        <p>Demolition. The Landlord, having obtained all necessary permits from the City, and having provided
               written notice to the Tenant pursuant to state law, seeks in good faith to recover
               possession of the Rental Unit to remove the Rental Unit permanently from rental housing
               use through demolition.</p>
        <p>(b)</p>
        <p>Relocation Assistance.</p>
        <p>(1)</p>
        <p>A landlord seeking to recover possession under Subsections (a)(6)-(9) herein shall
               provide Relocation Assistance to affected Tenant households. The Relocation Assistance
               required herein shall be a minimum amount. The City Council may increase the dollar
               amounts of Relocation Assistance pursuant to its powers under law. The Landlord shall
               notify the affected Tenants of their rights under this Subsection, if any, at the
               time of service of the notice to quit.</p>
        <p>(2)</p>
        <p>The Committee shall issue rules and regulations to effectuate this Subsection including
               but not limited to rules and regulations setting forth the procedures for establishing
               the amount of Relocation Assistance applicable to any given Tenant household, and
               for the reasonably timely payment of any applicable Relocation Assistance.</p>
        <p>(3)</p>
        <p>For purposes of this Article, Relocation Assistance shall be available to all Tenant
               households eligible under this Article whose household income does not exceed one-hundred-and-twenty
               percent (120%) of the median household income for Santa Clara County as adjusted for
               household size according to the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development.</p>
        <p>(c)</p>
        <p>First Right of Return. All Tenants whose tenancy is terminated based upon a basis enumerated in Subsections
               (a)(6)-(9) herein shall have the first right of return to the Rental Unit if that
               Rental Unit is returned to the market by the Landlord or successor Landlord. Rent
               for the Rental Unit shall be the Rent lawfully paid by the Tenant at the time the
               Landlord gave notice of termination based upon Subsections (a)(6)-(9) herein.</p>
        <p>(d)</p>
        <p>Retaliation is Barred. Notwithstanding the above provisions, no Landlord shall take action to terminate
               any tenancy or otherwise recover possession of a Rental Unit in retaliation for the
               Tenant reporting violations of this Article, for exercising rights granted under this
               Article, or for forming or participating in a Recognized Tenant Organization.</p>
        <p>(e)</p>
        <p>Notice to Specify Basis for Termination: Any notice purporting to terminate tenancy on any of the bases specified in this
               Section must state with specificity the basis on which the Landlord seeks to terminate
               the tenancy.</p>
        <p>(f)</p>
        <p>Landlord Compliance with this Article. In any action brought to recover possession of a Rental Unit, the Landlord shall
               allege compliance with this Article.</p>
        <p>(g)</p>
        <p>Filing Termination Notices with Committee. The Landlord shall file with the Committee a copy of any notice terminating tenancy
               within three (3) days after serving the notice on the Tenant.</p>
        <p>(h)</p>
        <p>Failure to comply. A Landlord's failure to comply with any requirement of this Article, including without
               limitation the failure to serve any of the required notices on the Committee pursuant
               to Subsection (g) herein, is a complete affirmative defense in an unlawful detainer
               or other action brought by the Landlord to recover possession of the Rental Unit.</p>
        <p>(As added November 8, 2016.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
