<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/part-i/article-xvii/section-1703">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Exemptions</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/part-i/article-xvii/section-1703"
             temporalId="sSection 1703">
      <num>Section 1703</num>
      <heading>Exemptions</heading>
      <content>
        <p>(a)</p>
        <p>Fully Exempt (Exempt from Both Rent Stabilization and Just Cause for Eviction). The following Rental Units are exempt from all provisions of this Article:</p>
        <p>(1)</p>
        <p>Units in hotels, motels, inns, tourist homes and rooming and boarding houses which
               are rented primarily to transient guests for a period of fewer than thirty (30) days
               as defined in Mountain View City Code section 33.1(d);</p>
        <p>(2)</p>
        <p>Rental Units in any hospital, convent, monastery, extended medical care facility,
               asylum, non-profit home for the aged, or dormitory owned and operated by an accredited
               institution of higher education;</p>
        <p>(3)</p>
        <p>Rental Units owned or operated or managed by a not-for-profit organization pursuant
               to a tax credit program;</p>
        <p>(4)</p>
        <p>Rental Units which a government unit, agency or authority owns, operates, or manages,
               or in which governmentally-subsidized Tenants reside, if applicable federal or state
               law or administrative regulation specifically exempt such units from municipal rent
               control;</p>
        <p>(5)</p>
        <p>Rental Units with first certificate of occupancy after the effective date of this
               Article; and</p>
        <p>(6)</p>
        <p>Rental Units additionally exempted pursuant to Section 1704.</p>
        <p>(b)</p>
        <p>Partially Exempt (Just Cause for Eviction Applies). The following Rental Units are
               exempt from Sections 1706, 1707, and 1708 of this Article (regarding Stabilization of Rents) and from Sections 1710 and 1711 (regarding Petitions for Individual Rent Adjustment), but are not exempt
               from Section 1705 (Just Cause for Eviction Protections):</p>
        <p>(1)</p>
        <p>Rental Units with an initial certificate of occupancy dated between February 1, 1995
               and the effective date of this Article; and</p>
        <p>(2)</p>
        <p>Rental Units governed by Mountain View City Code Chapter 36, Article XIV (&quot;Affordable Housing Program&quot;) to the extent permissible by law.</p>
        <p>(As added November 8, 2016.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
