<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/part-i/article-xvii/section-1710">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Petitions for individual rent adjustment—bases</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/part-i/article-xvii/section-1710"
             temporalId="sSection 1710">
      <num>Section 1710</num>
      <heading>Petitions for individual rent adjustment—bases</heading>
      <content>
        <p>A Landlord or a Tenant may file a Petition with the Committee seeking adjustment,
               either upward or downward, of the Rent for any given tenancy in accordance with the
               standards set forth in this Section, and using the procedures set forth in Section 1711 herein and implementing regulations. A Petition shall be on a form provided by the
               Committee and, if made by the Landlord, shall include a declaration by the Landlord
               that the Rental Unit complies with all requirements of this Article.</p>
        <p>(a)</p>
        <p>Petition for Upward Adjustment—Fair Rate of Return: To effectuate the purposes of this Article and the requirements of law, a Landlord
                  may file a Petition for an upward adjustment of the Rent to ensure a fair and reasonable
                  rate of return. It is the intent of this Article that individual upward adjustments
                  in Rent be granted only when the Landlord demonstrates that such adjustments are necessary
                  to provide the Landlord with a fair rate of return. The Committee shall promulgate
                  regulations to further govern Petitions filed pursuant to this Subsection in accordance
                  with law and the purposes of this Article.</p>
        <p>(1)</p>
        <p>Prerequisites. No upward adjustment of Rent shall be authorized by a Hearing Officer or the Committee
                  under this Subsection if the Landlord:</p>
        <p>(A)</p>
        <p>Has continued to fail to comply, after order of the Committee or other authority,
                  with any provisions of this Article or orders or regulations issued thereunder; or</p>
        <p>(B)</p>
        <p>Has failed to maintain the Rental Unit in compliance with Civil Code Sections 1941.1
                  et seq. and Health and Safety Code Sections 17920.3 and 17920.10.</p>
        <p>(2)</p>
        <p>Fair Rate of Return - Factors. In making any upward adjustment to the Rent based upon a Landlord's Petition to ensure
                  a fair rate of return, the Hearing Officer or Committee shall consider relevant factors,
                  including but not limited to, the following:</p>
        <p>(A)</p>
        <p>Increases or decreases in property taxes;</p>
        <p>(B)</p>
        <p>Unavoidable increases or any decreases in maintenance and operating expenses;</p>
        <p>(C)</p>
        <p>The cost of planned or completed capital improvements to the Rental Unit (as distinguished
                  from ordinary repair, replacement, and maintenance), but only where such capital improvements
                  are necessary to bring the Property into compliance or maintain compliance with applicable
                  local codes affecting health and safety, and where such capital improvement costs
                  are properly amortized over the life of the improvements;</p>
        <p>(D)</p>
        <p>Increases or decreases in the number of tenants occupying the Rental Unit, living
                  space, furniture, furnishings, equipment, or other Housing Services provided, or occupancy
                  rules;</p>
        <p>(E)</p>
        <p>Substantial deterioration of the Rental Unit other than as a result of normal wear
                  and tear;</p>
        <p>(F)</p>
        <p>Failure on the part of the Landlord to provide adequate Housing Services, or to comply
                  substantially with applicable state rental housing laws, local housing codes, health
                  and safety codes, or the Rental Housing Agreement; and</p>
        <p>(G)</p>
        <p>The pattern of recent Rent increases or decreases in the Rental Unit during the occupancy
                  of the current Tenant.</p>
        <p>(3)</p>
        <p>Fair Rate of Return - Factors Excluded. In making any upward adjustment to the Rent based upon a Landlord's Petition to ensure
                  a fair rate of return, the Hearing Officer or Committee shall not consider the following
                  factors as justifying an upward adjustment:</p>
        <p>(A)</p>
        <p>Costs of debt servicing (including but not limited to principal, interest, and fees)
                  for any debt obtained after October 19, 2015, other than debt incurred to finance
                  the cost of improvements as described in Subsection 1710(a)(2)(C);</p>
        <p>(B)</p>
        <p>Any penalties, fees, or interest assessed or awarded for violation of this or any
                  other law with respect to the Rental Unit;</p>
        <p>(C)</p>
        <p>The costs of capital improvements that are not necessary to bring the property into
                  compliance or maintain compliance with applicable local codes affecting health and
                  safety;</p>
        <p>(D)</p>
        <p>Cost increases, capital improvements, banked Annual General Adjustments, or other
                  circumstances that arose before the current tenancy began; and</p>
        <p>(E)</p>
        <p>Income taxes.</p>
        <p>(4)</p>
        <p>Effective Date of Individual Rent Adjustment. Rent increases authorized pursuant to this Subsection shall become effective only
                  after the Landlord provides the Tenant written notice of such Rent increase pursuant
                  to state law.</p>
        <p>(b)</p>
        <p>Petition for Downward Adjustment — Failure to Maintain Habitable Premises:</p>
        <p>(1)</p>
        <p>Failure to maintain a Rental Unit in compliance with governing health and safety and
                  building codes, including but not limited to Civil Code Sections 1941.1 et seq. and
                  Health and Safety Code Sections 17920.3 and 17920.10, constitutes an increase in Rent.
                  A Tenant may file a Petition with the Committee to adjust the Rent downward based
                  on a loss in rental value attributable to the Landlord's failure to maintain the Rental
                  Unit in habitable condition.</p>
        <p>(2)</p>
        <p>A Tenant Petition filed pursuant to this Subsection must specify the conditions alleged
                  to constitute the failure to maintain the Rental Unit in habitable condition and demonstrate
                  that the Landlord was provided with reasonable notice and opportunity to correct the
                  conditions that form the basis for the Petition.</p>
        <p>(c)</p>
        <p>Petition for Downward Adjustment — Decrease in Housing Services or Maintenance. A decrease in Housing Services or maintenance, or deterioration of the Rental Unit
                  beyond ordinary wear and tear, without a corresponding reduction in Rent, is considered
                  an increase in Rent. A Tenant may file a Petition to adjust the Rent downward based
                  on a loss in rental value attributable to a decrease in Housing Services or maintenance
                  or deterioration of the Rental Unit. The Petition must specify the circumstances allege
                  to constitute a decrease in Housing Services or maintenance, and demonstrate that
                  the Landlord was provided with reasonable notice and an opportunity to correct in
                  like manner to Petitions filed pursuant to Subsection 1710(b)(2) herein.</p>
        <p>(d)</p>
        <p>Petition for Downward Adjustment — Unlawful Rent: If a Landlord demands or retains Rent in excess of the lawful Rent pursuant to this
                  Article, a Tenant may file a Petition to adjust the Rent to its lawful level.</p>
        <p>(As added November 8, 2016.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
