<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/part-i/article-xvii/section-1711">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Petitions for individual rent adjustment—procedures</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/part-i/article-xvii/section-1711"
             temporalId="sSection 1711">
      <num>Section 1711</num>
      <heading>Petitions for individual rent adjustment—procedures</heading>
      <content>
        <p>The Committee shall promulgate regulations regarding procedures for Petitions filed
               under this Article. Petitions shall be governed by such regulations and by the provisions
               of this Section.</p>
        <p>(a)</p>
        <p>Hearing Officer. A Hearing Officer appointed by the Committee shall conduct a hearing to act upon
                  the Petition, and shall have the power to administer oaths and affirmations, and to
                  render a final decision on the merits of the Petition, subject to the provisions of
                  this Article.</p>
        <p>(b)</p>
        <p>Notice. The Committee shall notify the Landlord, if the Petition was filed by the Tenant,
                  or the Tenant, if the Petition was filed by the Landlord, of the receipt of such a
                  Petition and provide a copy thereof.</p>
        <p>(c)</p>
        <p>Time of Hearing. Each party to a Petition shall receive sufficient advance notice of the bases, theories,
                  and relevant documents to be presented by the other party(ies), and of the time, date,
                  and place of any hearing regarding the Petition.</p>
        <p>(d)</p>
        <p>Developing the Record. The Hearing Officer may require either party to a Petition to provide any books,
                  records, and papers deemed pertinent. If the Hearing Officer finds good cause to believe
                  that a building or other inspection would assist in resolving the issues raised by
                  the Petition, the Hearing Officer may conduct an inspection and/or request the City
                  to conduct an inspection. The Tenant may request the Hearing Officer to order such
                  an inspection prior to the date of the hearing. All documents required under this
                  Subsection shall be made available to the parties involved prior to the hearing.</p>
        <p>(e)</p>
        <p>Open Hearings. All hearings conducted pursuant to this Section shall be open to the public.</p>
        <p>(f)</p>
        <p>Right of Assistance. All parties to a hearing conducted pursuant to this Section may have assistance in
                  presenting evidence and developing their position from attorneys, legal workers, Recognized
                  Tenant Organization representatives, or any other persons designated by said parties.</p>
        <p>(g)</p>
        <p>Hearing Record. The Committee shall make available for inspection and copying any official record
                  that shall constitute the exclusive record for decision on the issues at the hearing.
                  The record of the hearing, or any part of one, shall be obtainable for the reasonable
                  cost of copying. All hearings shall be audio or video recorded, as ordered by the
                  Hearing Officer, and any party to the Petition may receive a copy of the recording
                  upon payment of a reasonable cost.</p>
        <p>(h)</p>
        <p>Quantum of Proof and Notice of Decision. No Petition for Individual Rent Adjustment, whether upward or downward, shall be
                  granted unless supported by the preponderance of the evidence submitted prior to and
                  at the hearing. All parties to a hearing shall be sent a notice of the decision and
                  a copy of the findings of fact and law upon which said decision is based. At the same
                  time, parties to the proceeding shall also be notified of their right to appeal to
                  the Committee and/or to judicial review.</p>
        <p>(i)</p>
        <p>Consolidation. Whether submitted by a Landlord or Tenant(s), all Petitions pertaining to Rental
                  Units at the same Property may be consolidated for hearing upon a showing of good
                  cause.</p>
        <p>(j)</p>
        <p>Appeal. Any person aggrieved by the decision of the Hearing Officer may appeal to the full
                  Committee for review. On appeal, the Committee shall affirm, reverse, or modify the
                  decision of the Hearing Officer. The decision on appeal shall be based on the hearing
                  record, and the Committee shall neither hear nor find facts in addition to those presented
                  to the Hearing Officer.</p>
        <p>(k)</p>
        <p>Finality of Decision. The decision of the Hearing Officer shall be the final decision of the Committee,
                  unless an aggrieved party has timely sought an appeal to the Committee. The decision
                  of the Committee on appeal shall be final unless an aggrieved party has timely sought
                  judicial review pursuant to law.</p>
        <p>(l)</p>
        <p>Time for Decision. A final decision on any Petition shall be made within a reasonable time. Decisions
                  decreasing Rent shall remain in effect until the Landlord has corrected the defect
                  warranting the decrease. The Committee shall, by regulation, establish procedures
                  for making prompt compliance determinations.</p>
        <p>(m)</p>
        <p>Right to Fair Return Guaranteed. No provision of this Article shall be applied so as to prohibit the Committee from
                  granting an Individual Rent Adjustment that is demonstrated by the Landlord to be
                  necessary to provide the Landlord with a fair rate of return.</p>
        <p>(As added November 8, 2016.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
