<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/part-i/article-xvii/section-1702">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Definitions</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/part-i/article-xvii/section-1702"
             temporalId="sSection 1702">
      <num>Section 1702</num>
      <heading>Definitions</heading>
      <content>
        <p>Unless further defined elsewhere in this Article, the following words or phrases as
               used in this Article shall have the following meanings:</p>
        <p>(a)</p>
        <p>Annual General Adjustment. The Annual General Adjustment is the percentage by which the Rent for existing tenancies
                  in Covered Rental Units may be increased each year, subject to the limitations of
                  this Article.</p>
        <p>(b)</p>
        <p>Base Rent. The Base Rent is the reference point from which the lawful Rent shall be determined
                  and adjusted in accordance with this Article.</p>
        <p>(1)</p>
        <p>Tenancies commencing on or before October 19, 2015. The Base Rent for tenancies that
                  commenced on or before October 19, 2015 shall be the Rent in effect on October 19,
                  2015.</p>
        <p>(2)</p>
        <p>Tenancies commencing after October 19, 2015. The Base Rent for tenancies that commenced
                  after October 19, 2015 shall be the initial rental rate charged upon initial occupancy,
                  provided that amount is not a violation of this Article or any provision of state
                  law. The term &quot;initial rental rate&quot; means only the amount of Rent actually paid by
                  the Tenant for the initial term of the tenancy.</p>
        <p>(c)</p>
        <p>Committee. The term &quot;Committee&quot; refers to the Mountain View Rental Housing Committee established
                  by this Article.</p>
        <p>(d)</p>
        <p>Covered Rental Units. All Rental Units not specifically exempted by this Article.</p>
        <p>(e)</p>
        <p>City Council. The term &quot;City Council&quot; refers to the City Council of the City of Mountain View.</p>
        <p>(f)</p>
        <p>Disabled. The term &quot;Disabled&quot; is defined in Govt. Code Section 12955.3.</p>
        <p>(g)</p>
        <p>Hearing Officer. An official appointed by the Committee to conduct an investigation or administrative
                  hearing pursuant to this Article.</p>
        <p>(h)</p>
        <p>Housing Services. Housing Services include, but are not limited to, repairs, maintenance, painting,
                  providing light, hot and cold water, elevator service, window shades and screens,
                  storage, kitchen, bath and laundry facilities and privileges, janitor services, Utility
                  Charges that are paid by the Landlord, refuse removal, furnishings, telephone, parking,
                  the right to have a specified number of occupants, and any other benefit, privilege
                  or facility connected with the use or occupancy of any Rental Unit. Housing Services
                  to a Rental Unit shall include a proportionate part of services provided to common
                  facilities of the building in which the Rental Unit is contained.</p>
        <p>(i)</p>
        <p>Individual Rent Adjustment. An adjustment to the otherwise lawful Rent authorized by a Hearing Officer or the
                  Committee pursuant to this Article.</p>
        <p>(j)</p>
        <p>Landlord. An owner, lessor, sublessor or any other person entitled to receive Rent for the
                  use and occupancy of any Rental Unit, or an agent, representative, predecessor, or
                  successor of any of the foregoing.</p>
        <p>(k)</p>
        <p>Petition. A petition for Individual Rent Adjustment pursuant to this Article.</p>
        <p>(l)</p>
        <p>Primary Residence. The occupant's usual place of return. To classify a unit as an occupant's Primary
                  Residence does not require that the occupant be physically present in the unit at
                  all times or continuously, but does require that the unit be the occupant's usual
                  place of return. Factors that are indicative of Primary Residence include but are
                  not limited to:</p>
        <p>(1)</p>
        <p>The occupant carries on basic living activities at the subject premises for extended
                  periods;</p>
        <p>(2)</p>
        <p>The subject premises are listed with public agencies, including but not limited to
                  federal, state and local taxing authorities, as the occupant's primary residence;</p>
        <p>(3)</p>
        <p>Utility Charges and other charges and fees associated with usage of the structure
                  are billed to and paid by the occupant at the subject premises;</p>
        <p>(4)</p>
        <p>The occupant does not file for a homeowner's tax exemption for any different property;</p>
        <p>(5)</p>
        <p>The occupant is not registered to vote at any other location; and</p>
        <p>(6)</p>
        <p>Ownership is held in the name of the occupant claiming Primary Residence and not held
                  by a Limited Liability Corporation or other corporate or business entity structure.</p>
        <p>(m)</p>
        <p>Property. All Rental Units on a parcel or lot or contiguous parcels or contiguous lots under
                  common ownership.</p>
        <p>(n)</p>
        <p>Recognized Tenant Organization. Any group of Tenants residing in Rental Units in the same building or in different
                  buildings operated by the same management company, agent or Landlord, who choose to
                  be so designated. This shall also include any other at-large organization that represents
                  the interest of Tenants.</p>
        <p>(o)</p>
        <p>Relocation Assistance. Financial assistance in the amounts set forth in Mountain View City Code, Article
                  XIII, sections 36.38.15, including without limitation Subsection 36.38.15(d) regarding &quot;Special-circumstances&quot; households as defined in Mountain View City
                  Code, Article XIII, sections 36.38.05(g).</p>
        <p>(p)</p>
        <p>Rent. All periodic payments and all nonmonetary consideration including, but not limited
                  to, the fair market value of goods, labor performed or services rendered to or for
                  the benefit of the Landlord under a Rental Housing Agreement concerning the use or
                  occupancy of a Rental Unit and premises and attendant Housing Services, including
                  all payment and consideration demanded or paid for parking, Utility Charges, pets,
                  furniture, and/or subletting.</p>
        <p>(q)</p>
        <p>Rental Housing Agreement. An agreement, oral, written, or implied, between a Landlord and Tenant for use or
                  occupancy of a Rental Unit and for Housing Services.</p>
        <p>(r)</p>
        <p>Rental Housing Fee. The fee described in Subsection 1709(j)(1) herein.</p>
        <p>(s)</p>
        <p>Rental Unit. Any building, structure, or part thereof, or land appurtenant thereto, or any other
                  rental property rented or offered for rent for residential purposes, together with
                  all Housing Services connected with use or occupancy of such property, such as common
                  areas and recreational facilities held out for use by the Tenant.</p>
        <p>(t)</p>
        <p>Single-Family Home. A detached building containing a single residential dwelling unit separately alienable
                  from any other dwelling unit.</p>
        <p>(u)</p>
        <p>Tenant. A Tenant, subtenant, lessee, sublessee or any other person entitled under the terms
                  of a Rental Housing Agreement or this Article to the use or occupancy of any Rental
                  Unit.</p>
        <p>(v)</p>
        <p>Utility Charges. Any charges for gas, electricity, water, garbage, sewer, telephone, cable, internet,
                  or other service relating to the use and occupancy of a Rental Unit.</p>
        <p>(w)</p>
        <p>Written Notice to Cease. A written notice provided by a Landlord that gives a Tenant an opportunity to cure
                  an alleged violation or problem prior to service of a notice to terminate tenancy.
                  Any Written Notice to Cease must:</p>
        <p>(1)</p>
        <p>Provide the Tenant a reasonable period to cure the alleged violation or problem;</p>
        <p>(2)</p>
        <p>Inform the Tenant that failure to cure may result in the initiation of eviction proceedings;</p>
        <p>(3)</p>
        <p>Inform the Tenant of the right to request a reasonable accommodation;</p>
        <p>(4)</p>
        <p>Inform the Tenant of the contact number for the Committee; and</p>
        <p>(5)</p>
        <p>Include sufficient details about the conduct underlying the Written Notice to Cease
                  that allow a reasonable person to comply.</p>
        <p>(As added November 8, 2016.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
