<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/part-i/article-xvii/section-1707">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Rent increases pursuant to annual general adjustment</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/part-i/article-xvii/section-1707"
             temporalId="sSection 1707">
      <num>Section 1707</num>
      <heading>Rent increases pursuant to annual general adjustment</heading>
      <content>
        <p>(a)</p>
        <p>Annual General Adjustment. No later than June 30th each year, the Committee shall announce the amount of the
               Annual General Adjustment, which shall be effective as of September 1st of that year.
               The Annual General Adjustment is the percentage by which the Rent for existing tenancies
               in Covered Rental Units may be increased each year, subject to the limitations of
               this Article.</p>
        <p>(1)</p>
        <p>The Annual General Adjustment shall be equal to one hundred percent (100%) of the
               percentage increase in the Consumer Price Index (All Urban Consumers, San Francisco-Oakland-San
               Jose region, or any successor designation of that index that may later be adopted
               by the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics) as reported and published by the U.S. Department
               of Labor, Bureau of Labor Statistics, for the twelve-month period ending as of March
               of the current year. The Annual General Adjustment shall be rounded to the nearest
               one-tenth of a percent.</p>
        <p>(2)</p>
        <p>Subparagraph 1 of this Subsection notwithstanding, in no event shall the Annual General
               Adjustment be less than two percent (2%) or more than five percent (5%).</p>
        <p>(3)</p>
        <p>Pursuant to Subsection (a) herein, the Committee's first announcement of an Annual
               General Adjustment shall be made no later than June 30, 2017. Accordingly, the first
               Rent increase that a Landlord may impose pursuant to this Article shall not take effect
               prior to September 1, 2017.</p>
        <p>(b)</p>
        <p>One Rent Increase Per Year. No more than one Rent increase per twelve-month period may be imposed on a Tenant.</p>
        <p>(c)</p>
        <p>Notice of Rent Increase Required. Allowable Rent increases pursuant to the Annual General Adjustment shall become effective
               only after the Landlord provides written notice to the Tenant in the manner prescribed
               by law, with at least thirty (30) days' advance written notice.</p>
        <p>(d)</p>
        <p>Banking of Unimplemented Annual General Adjustments. A Landlord who refrains from imposing a Rent increase or any portion thereof pursuant
               to an Annual General Adjustment may accumulate said increase and impose the unimplemented
               amount in subsequent years. The ability to accumulate and impose unimplemented Rent
               increases shall not carry over to a successor Landlord in the event of a change in
               ownership of the Rental Unit. Any such subsequent Rent increase shall be subject to
               the limitations of this section, including the 10% limitation in Subsection (e) herein.
               The Committee may issue rules and regulations that modify, restrict, or prohibit the
               ability of Landlords to impose accumulated increases upon a finding that the banking
               of Annual General Adjustments causes undue hardship on Tenants, provided that Landlords
               retain their right to a fair return.</p>
        <p>(e)</p>
        <p>10% Annual Rent Increase Limit. The overall Rent increase in any twelve-month period shall not exceed ten percent
               (10%) of the Rent actually charged to the Tenant. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the
               overall Rent increase in any twelve-month period may exceed ten-percent (10%) of the
               Rent actually charged to the Tenant only if that Rent increase is pursuant to a decision
               of a Hearing Officer or the Committee as a result of a Landlord Petition pursuant
               to Section 1710(a) of this Article.</p>
        <p>(f)</p>
        <p>Conditions Under Which Rent Increase Not Permitted. No Rent increase shall be effective if the Landlord:</p>
        <p>(1)</p>
        <p>Has failed to substantially comply with all provisions of this Article and all rules
               and regulations promulgated by the Committee; or</p>
        <p>(2)</p>
        <p>Has failed to maintain the Rental Unit in compliance with Civil Code Sections 1941.1
               et seq. and Health and Safety Code Sections 17920.3 and 17920.10; or</p>
        <p>(3)</p>
        <p>Has failed to make repairs ordered by a Hearing Officer, the Committee, or the City.</p>
        <p>(As added November 8, 2016.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
