<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/section-mountain-view">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>City Code</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/section-mountain-view"
             temporalId="sMOUNTAIN VIEW">
      <num>MOUNTAIN VIEW</num>
      <heading>City Code</heading>
      <content>
        <p>____________</p>
        <p>A Codification of the General Ordinancesof the City of Mountain View, California</p>
        <p>____________</p>
        <p>Codified 1938</p>
        <p>____________</p>
        <p>Beginning with Supp. No. 18,Supplemented by Municipal Code Corporation</p>
        <p>____________</p>
        <p>SUPPLEMENT PREFACE</p>
        <p>The Mountain View, California Municipal Code has been kept current by regular supplementation
            by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc., its successor in interest.</p>
        <p>Beginning with Supplement No. 18, Municipal Code Corporation will be keeping this
            Code current by regular supplementation.</p>
        <p>This supplement brings the Code up to date through Ordinance No. 10.2025, passed December 28, 2025.</p>
        <p>Municipal Code Corporation
               
               1700 Capital Circle SW
               
               Tallahassee, FL 32310
               
               800-262-2633</p>
        <p>HOW TO USE YOUR CODE</p>
        <p>This code is organized to make the laws of the city as accessible as possible to city
            officials, city employees and private citizens. Please take a moment to familiarize
            yourself with some of the important elements of this code.</p>
        <p>Numbering System.</p>
        <p>The numbering system is the backbone of a Code of Ordinances; Municipal Code Corporation
            uses a unique and versatile numbering structure that allows for easy expansion and
            amendment of this Code. It is based on two tiers, beginning with chapter and ending
            with section. Each part is represented in the code section number. For example, Section 2.4 is Section 4 in Chapter 2.</p>
        <p>Chapter.</p>
        <p>A chapter is a broad category under which ordinances on a related subject are compiled.
            This code contains about 40 chapters. For example, the first chapter is Chapter 1, General Provisions, which may contain ordinances about the general penalty, code
            adoption and definitions. The chapters in this code are separated by tabbed divider
            pages for quick reference.</p>
        <p>Section.</p>
        <p>Each section of the code contains substantive ordinance material.</p>
        <p>Table of Contents.</p>
        <p>At the beginning of the code is the main table of contents listing each chapter, as
            well as subordinate articles and division.</p>
        <p>Ordinance History Note.</p>
        <p>At the end of each code section, you will find an &quot;ordinance history note,&quot; which
            lists the underlying ordinances for that section. The ordinances are listed by number,
            section (if applicable) and year. (Example: (Ord. 272 § 1, 1992).)</p>
        <p>Correlation Table.</p>
        <p>To find a specific ordinance in the code, turn to the section called &quot;Correlation
            Table.&quot; This table tells you the status of every ordinance included in the code. The
            table is organized by ordinance number and provides a disposition of the ordinance.
            The chapter (or chapters) affected is indicated.</p>
        <p>Beginning with Supplement No. 18, this table will be replaced with the &quot;Code Comparative
            Table and Disposition List.&quot;</p>
        <p>Code Comparative Table and Disposition List.</p>
        <p>Beginning with Supplement No. 18, a Code Comparative Table and Disposition List has
            been added for use in tracking legislative history. Located in the back of this volume,
            this table is a chronological listing of each ordinance considered for codification.
            The Code Comparative Table and Disposition List specifies the ordinance number, adoption
            date, description of the ordinance and the disposition within the code of each ordinance.
            By use of the Code Comparative Table and Disposition List, the reader can locate any
            section of the code as supplemented, and any subsequent ordinance included herein.</p>
        <p>Index.</p>
        <p>If you are not certain where to look for a particular subject in this code, start
            with the index. This is an alphabetical multi-tier subject index which uses section
            numbers as the reference, and cross-references where necessary. Look for the main
            heading of the subject you need, then the appropriate subheadings. The index will
            be updated as necessary when the code text is amended.</p>
        <p>Instruction Sheet.</p>
        <p>Each supplement to the new code will be accompanied by an Instruction Sheet. This
            will tell the code user the date of the most recent supplement and the last ordinance
            contained in that supplement. It will then list the pages that must be pulled from
            the code and the new pages that must be inserted. Following these instructions carefully
            will ensure that the code is kept accurate and current. Removed pages should be kept
            for future reference.</p>
        <p>Electronic Submission.</p>
        <p>In the interests of accuracy and speed, we encourage you to submit your ordinances
            electronically if at all possible. We can accept most any file format, including Word,
            WordPerfect or text files. We prefer Word, any version. You can send files to us as
            an e-mail attachment, by FTP, on a diskette or CD-ROM. Electronic files enable us
            not only to get you your code more quickly but also ensure that it is error-free.
            Our e-mail address is: ords@municode.com.</p>
        <p>For hard copy, send two copies of all ordinances passed to:</p>
        <p>Municipal Code Corporation
            
            P.O. Box 2235
            
            Tallahassee, FL 32316</p>
        <p>Customer Service.</p>
        <p>If you have any questions about this code or our services, please contact Municipal
            Code Corporation at 1-800-262-2633 or:</p>
        <p>Municipal Code Corporation
               
               1700 Capital Circle SW
               
               Tallahassee, FL 32310</p>
        <p>CODE ADOPTION</p>
        <p>ORDINANCE NO. 1.69</p>
        <p>AN ORDINANCE OF THE CITY OF MOUNTAIN VIEW, CALIFORNIA, ADOPTING A REVISION AND RECODIFICATION
               OF THE ORDINANCES AND CODE OF THE CITY OF MOUNTAIN VIEW, ENTITLED, &quot;THE CODE OF THE
               CITY OF MOUNTAIN VIEW, CALIFORNIA,&quot; PROVIDING FOR THE REPEAL OF CERTAIN ORDINANCES
               NOT INCLUDED THEREIN WITH CERTAIN EXCEPTIONS AND FOR OTHER PURPOSES HEREINAFTER SET
               OUT.</p>
        <p>The City Council of the City of Mountain View does ordinance as follows:</p>
        <p>SECTION 1. There is hereby adopted by the City of Mountain View that certain Code entitled,
               &quot;The Code of the City of Mountain View, California,&quot; containing certain ordinances
               of a general and permanent nature as compiled, consolidated, recodified and indexed
               in chapters, namely, Chapters 1 to 37 both inclusive, of which Code not less than three copies have been and are
               now filed in the office of the City Clerk and which is hereby referred to and adopted
               by reference as if incorporated and set out at length in this ordinance.</p>
        <p>SECTION 2. The provisions of such Code shall being force on and after February 27, 1969, and
               the previous Code and all ordinances of a general and permanent nature in force on
               January 27, 1969, and not contained in such Code hereby adopted are repealed from
               and after February 27, 1969, except as hereinafter provided.</p>
        <p>SECTION 3. The repeal provided for in the preceding section of this ordinance shall not affect
               any offense or act committed or done or any penalty or forfeiture incurred or any
               contract or right established or accruing before February 27, 1969; nor shall such
               repeal affect any ordinance or resolution promising or guaranteeing the payment of
               money by the city or authorizing the issue of any bonds of the city or any evidence
               of the city's indebtedness or any contract or obligation assumed by the city; nor
               shall such repeal affect the administrative ordinances or resolutions of the Council
               not in conflict or inconsistent with the provisions of such Code; nor shall it affect
               the annual tax levy; nor shall it affect any right or franchise conferred by ordinance
               or resolution of the city on any person or corporation, nor shall it affect any ordinance
               relating to the salaries of the officers or employees; nor shall it affect any ordinance
               annexing territory to the city; nor shall it affect any ordinance naming, opening,
               accepting or vacating streets or alleys in the city; nor shall it affect any ordinance
               relating to zoning; nor shall it affect Sections 475,476,601,602,603 and 604 of the
               1938 Code of the city; nor shall it affect sections 520 to 557 of the 1938 Code of the city, as amended by Ordinance No. 175.47, Ordinance
               No. 175.374 and Ordinance No. 78.64; nor shall it affect Section 480 and Sections
               487 to 496 of the 1938 Code of the city; nor shall it affect any suspended ordinance
               concerning sales and use taxes in the city.</p>
        <p>SECTION 4. That, except as otherwise specifically provided, any violation of such Code shall
               be punishable by a fine not exceeding five hundred dollars or imprisonment for a term
               not exceeding six months, or by both such fine and imprisonment.</p>
        <p>SECTION 5. If any section, subsection, sentence, clause, phrase, or portion of this ordinance
               is for any reason held to be invalid or unconstitutional by the decision of any court
               of competent jurisdiction, such decision shall not affect the validity of the remaining
               portions of this ordinance. The City Council of the City of Mountain View hereby declares
               that it would have adopted this ordinance and each section, subsection, sentence,
               clause, phrase, or portion thereof, irrespective of the fact that any one or more
               sections, subsections, sentences, clauses, phrases, or portions be declared invalid
               or unconstitutional.</p>
        <p>The foregoing ordinance was regularly introduced at a Regular Meeting of the City
               Council of the City of Mountain View duly held on the 13th day of January, 1969 and
               was thereafter adopted at an adjourned Regular Meeting held on the 27th day of January,
               1969 by the following roll call vote:</p>
        <p>AYES: Councilmen Anderson, Cusimano, Gordon, Herfurth, Wollard and Mayor Jelavich</p>
        <p>NOES: None</p>
        <p>ABSENT: Councilman Thornall</p>
        <p>NOT</p>
        <p>VOTING: None</p>
        <p>APPROVED:</p>
        <p>/s/ 
                              WILLIAM R. JELAVICH
                              
									      
                              Mayor</p>
        <p>ATTEST:</p>
        <p>Jean Hixson</p>
        <p>City Clerk</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
