<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/part-i/article-v/section-503">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Compensation</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/part-i/article-v/section-503"
             temporalId="sSection 503">
      <num>Section 503</num>
      <heading>Compensation</heading>
      <content>
        <p>Each member of the city council shall receive as salary, each month, that sum which
               has been established by the electorate as of November 4, 2014, as the baseline salary
               amount of one thousand dollars ($1,000) per month with automatic annual adjustments
               based on the lesser of the San Francisco Bay Area Consumer Price Index for urban wage
               earners or the average cost-of-living adjustment granted to the miscellaneous city
               employee bargaining groups and not to exceed five percent (5%) per year. The mayor
               shall receive as salary, each month, that amount as calculated for a councilmember
               above, plus an additional twenty-five percent (25%) of said sum. Any amounts paid
               to a councilmember for retirement, health and welfare, and federal Social Security
               benefits shall not be included for purposes of determining salary pursuant to this
               section provided the same benefits are available and paid by the city for its employees.
               Notwithstanding the foregoing, the city council shall have no power to increase its
               salary by ordinance, resolution or motion. If a member of the city council, or mayor,
               does not attend all regular meetings of the city council called on order of the city
               council and held during the month, that person's salary for such month shall be reduced
               by the sum of twenty-five dollars ($25) for each regular meeting not attended unless
               that person is absent with the consent of the mayor or for official city business.</p>
        <p>(As amended, April 9, 1968; June 3, 1980; November 6, 1984; November 4, 2014.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
