<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-5/article-i/section-sec.-5.4">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Conditions related only to seizures of dogs running at large</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-5/article-i/section-sec.-5.4"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 5_4">
      <num>SEC. 5.4</num>
      <heading>Conditions related only to seizures of dogs running at large</heading>
      <content>
        <p>An animal control officer shall not seize or impound a dog for running at large in
               violation of Sec. 5.50 when the dog has not strayed from and is upon private property owned by the dog owner
               or the person who has a right to control the dog, or upon private property to which
               the dog owner or person who has a right to control the dog has a right of possession.</p>
        <p>A dog that has strayed from but then returned to the private property of its owner
               or the person who has a right to control the dog shall not be seized or impounded
               merely for violation of Sec. 5.50, but in such a case, a citation for such violation may be issued; provided, however,
               that if in such a situation, the owner or the person who has a right to control the
               dog is not available at the premises, the dog may be impounded, but the officer shall
               post a notice of such impoundment on the front door of the living unit or other conspicuous
               place on the property of the owner or person who has a right to control the dog. This
               notice shall state the following: that the dog has been impounded, where the dog is
               being held, the name, address and telephone number of the agency or person to be contacted
               regarding release of the dog, and an indication of the ultimate disposition of the
               dog if no action to regain it is taken within a specified period of time by its owner
               or by the person who has a right to control the dog.</p>
        <p>This section shall not otherwise affect the authority of an animal control officer
               to seize or impound a dog or issue citations as a result of the violation of other
               sections of this chapter.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 4.14, § 1, 4/8/14.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
