<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-iii/section-sec.-2.56.1">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Cable communication system franchises</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-iii/section-sec.-2.56.1"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 2_56_1">
      <num>SEC. 2.56.1</num>
      <heading>Cable communication system franchises</heading>
      <content>
        <p>This section shall govern the procedures for granting all cable communications system
               franchises, and shall supersede and pre-empt all other code sections governing the
               procedure for granting franchises, except Chapter 37 herein.</p>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>When and if the city council, in its sole discretion, determines that it is in the
                  public interest to entertain applications for a cable communication system franchise,
                  it shall cause public notice to be given. Such public notice shall be designed to
                  elicit a high response from the cable communication system industry so that a maximum
                  number of competitive applications will be received.</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>After said cable communication system franchise applications have been received and
                  reviewed, a public hearing shall be held, after public notice, for the purpose of
                  hearing public comment on the cable communication system franchise applications. Protests
                  may also be received and considered at said public hearing, either in writing or verbally,
                  concerning the granting of such a cable communication system franchise.</p>
        <p>c.</p>
        <p>After the conclusion of said hearing, a cable communication system franchise may be
                  awarded under terms and conditions to be determined by the city council.</p>
        <p>d.</p>
        <p>All proceedings that have taken place in furtherance of the granting of a cable communication
                  system franchise prior to the adoption of this ordinance conform to the procedures
                  herein specified, and those proceedings are hereby ratified and validated.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 14.81, 8/31/81.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
