<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-3/article-iv/section-sec.-3.50">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Statement of findings</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-3/article-iv/section-sec.-3.50"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 3_50">
      <num>SEC. 3.50</num>
      <heading>Statement of findings</heading>
      <content>
        <p>The city council of the City of Mountain View hereby makes the following findings:</p>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>Approximately sixty-four percent (64%) of the city's total housing units are multiple-family
                  dwellings in character (i.e., apartment houses and condominium projects);</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>Well in excess of fifty percent (50%) of the city's total population resides in such
                  multiple-family residential dwellings;</p>
        <p>c.</p>
        <p>Because of the unique composition and patterns of the city's housing stock and percentage
                  of persons living in multiple-family dwellings, it has been found that such modes
                  of residence have created barriers and impediments to such persons receiving information
                  of political and social significance; and, as a result thereof, such persons have
                  not identified with or become involved in the political processes of the city, or
                  of the county, state or federal governments;</p>
        <p>d.</p>
        <p>Door-to-door political canvassing has historically been found to be a most effective
                  instrument in promoting the free and full discussion of political ideas; thereby promoting
                  and benefitting the health, safety and welfare of the citizens of the entire community;</p>
        <p>e.</p>
        <p>A compelling need therefore exists to establish procedures which have as their basis
                  the assimilation of persons living in multiple-family dwellings into the political
                  processes of the city, and of the county, state and federal governments, by helping
                  to inform such persons regarding candidates, political parties and ballot measures
                  of community-wide, statewide or nationwide importance, so that the public interest
                  would be served by having an informed and educated electorate;</p>
        <p>f.</p>
        <p>It is therefore the intent of this article to establish a procedure to ensure that
                  residents of multiple-family dwellings be accorded the same rights to receive political
                  information, in both oral and written form, as are persons who reside in single-family
                  detached residences; said procedure being that of granting political canvassers certain
                  corresponding rights to gain access to the common areas of multiple-family residential
                  facilities so as to be able to contact, on a door-to-door basis, the persons residing
                  within such residential facilities.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 39.78, 10/30/78.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
