<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-3/article-iv/section-sec.-3.52">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Definitions</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-3/article-iv/section-sec.-3.52"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 3_52">
      <num>SEC. 3.52</num>
      <heading>Definitions</heading>
      <content>
        <p>For the purposes of this article, the words and phrases used herein shall have the
               following meanings unless the context shows a different meaning:</p>
        <p>(a)</p>
        <p>&quot;Apartment house&quot; shall mean a group of five (5) or more attached, detached or semi-detached
                  rentable units, occupying a single parcel of land in one ownership, and having a yard
                  or court in common, and where cooking, bathroom and toilet facilities are available
                  in each respective unit.</p>
        <p>(b)</p>
        <p>&quot;Apartment house common areas&quot; shall mean those areas on or within an apartment house,
                  such as interior reception and lobby areas, interior hallways and stairwells, elevators,
                  exterior hallways, recreational areas, driveways, walkways, landscaped areas, and
                  off-street vehicular parking areas; which areas are not deemed to be individual dwelling
                  units for rental, letting or leasing.</p>
        <p>(c)</p>
        <p>&quot;Candidate&quot; shall mean that term as is defined in Section 11513 of the Elections Code
                  of the state, or successor section.</p>
        <p>(d)</p>
        <p>&quot;Common green subdivision&quot; shall mean that term as is defined in Section 28.8 of Article II of Chapter 28 of this code, or successor section.</p>
        <p>(e)</p>
        <p>&quot;Condominium&quot; shall mean that term as is defined in Section 783 of the Civil Code
                  of the state, or successor section.</p>
        <p>(f)</p>
        <p>&quot;Condominium project&quot; shall mean that term as is defined in Subsection 3 of Section
                  1350 of the Civil Code of the state, or successor section.</p>
        <p>(g)</p>
        <p>&quot;Condominium unit&quot; shall mean that term as defined in Subsection 2 of Section 1350
                  of the Civil Code of the state, or successor section.</p>
        <p>(h)</p>
        <p>&quot;Condominium project common areas&quot; shall mean those areas on or within a condominium
                  project, such as interior reception and lobby areas, interior hallways and stairwells,
                  elevators, exterior hallways, recreational areas, sidewalks, driveways, off-street
                  vehicular parking areas, and landscaped areas; which areas are owned in common by
                  the condominium unit owners or by a nonprofit corporation; and which areas are not
                  included within the definition of condominium unit.</p>
        <p>(i)</p>
        <p>&quot;Election&quot; shall mean any type of election specified and defined pursuant to provisions
                  of the Elections Code of the state, as well as any general municipal election provided
                  for in Section 1300 of the Charter of the City of Mountain View or any special municipal election provided
                  for in Section 1301 of the Charter of the City of Mountain View; and shall include the initiative, referendum
                  and recall.</p>
        <p>(j)</p>
        <p>&quot;Elective office&quot; shall mean that term as is defined in Section 11513.5 of the Elections
                  Code of the state, or successor section.</p>
        <p>(k)</p>
        <p>&quot;Measure&quot; shall mean that term as is defined in Section 11514 of the Elections Code
                  of the state, or successor section.</p>
        <p>(l)</p>
        <p>&quot;Mobile home lot&quot; shall mean that term as is defined in Sec. 36.3.46.1 of Article
                  I of Chapter 36 of this code, or successor section.</p>
        <p>(m)</p>
        <p>&quot;Mobile home&quot; shall mean that term as is defined in Sec. 36.3.46.2 of Article I of
                  Chapter 36 of this code, or successor section.</p>
        <p>(n)</p>
        <p>&quot;Mobile home park&quot; shall mean that term as is defined in Sec. 36.3.46.3 of Article
                  I of Chapter 36 of this code, or successor section.</p>
        <p>(o)</p>
        <p>&quot;Mobile home park common areas&quot; shall mean those areas within the confines of a mobile
                  home park, such as recreational areas, sidewalks, driveways, walkways, off-street
                  vehicular parking areas, and landscaped areas; which areas are not included within
                  the definition of mobile home lot.</p>
        <p>(p)</p>
        <p>&quot;Owner&quot; shall be further defined as follows:</p>
        <p>(i)</p>
        <p>In the case of an apartment house, owner shall mean that person who owns the apartment
                  house building or buildings;</p>
        <p>(ii)</p>
        <p>In the case of a condominium project or planned unit development in which the individual
                  condominium unit owners or lot owners jointly hold undivided ownership interests in
                  the common areas, owner shall mean each condominium unit owner or lot owner;</p>
        <p>(iii)</p>
        <p>In the case of a condominium project or planned unit development in which the common
                  areas are owned by a nonprofit corporation, owner shall mean such nonprofit corporation;</p>
        <p>(iv)</p>
        <p>In the case of a mobile home park, owner, shall mean the person who owns the mobile
                  home park itself;</p>
        <p>(v)</p>
        <p>In all cases, owner shall include the resident manager or other authorized representative
                  of an owner, whether or not such authorized representative resides on the premises.</p>
        <p>(q)</p>
        <p>&quot;Person&quot; shall mean any individual, group of individuals, partnerships of every kind,
                  corporation, unincorporated association, business or common law trust.</p>
        <p>(r)</p>
        <p>&quot;Planned unit development&quot; shall mean the same term as is defined as a common green
                  subdivision in subsection (d) of this section.</p>
        <p>(s)</p>
        <p>&quot;Planned unit development common areas&quot; shall mean those areas within the confines
                  of a planned unit development, such as driveways, off-street vehicular parking areas,
                  recreational areas, landscaped areas and walkways; which areas are owned in common
                  by the owners of the various lots within the planned unit development itself or by
                  a nonprofit corporation.</p>
        <p>(t)</p>
        <p>&quot;Political canvasser&quot; shall mean any individual who desires to gain entrance or access
                  to the common areas located within any apartment house, condominium project, mobile
                  home park or planned unit development so as to contact, on a door-to-door basis, the
                  persons residing or occupying dwelling units located within such residential facility,
                  for the purpose of disseminating political information or literature on behalf of,
                  and/or for soliciting contributions to, any candidate for elective office, political
                  party or measure.</p>
        <p>(u)</p>
        <p>&quot;Political party&quot; shall mean any political party which has qualified for participation
                  in any election pursuant to the provisions of Division 7 (commencing with Section
                  8000) of the Elections Code of the state.</p>
        <p>(v)</p>
        <p>&quot;Singular and plural&quot;: Whenever the singular form of a word or term is used in this
                  article, the same shall include the plural form of the word or term.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 39.78, 10/30/78.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
