<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-1/article-iii/section-sec.-1.35">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Claims</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-1/article-iii/section-sec.-1.35"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 1_35">
      <num>SEC. 1.35</num>
      <heading>Claims</heading>
      <content>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>Authority. This section is enacted pursuant to Section 935 of the California Government Code.</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>Claims required. All claims against the city for money or damages not otherwise governed by the Government
               Claims Act, California Government Code Sections
               
               900,
               
               et seq. or another state law (hereinafter in this section, &quot;claims&quot;) shall be presented
               within the time and in the manner prescribed by Part 3 of Division 3.6 of Title 1
               of the California Government Code (commencing with Section 900 thereof) for the claims
               to which that part applies by its own terms as those provisions now exist or shall
               hereafter be amended, and as further provided by this section.</p>
        <p>c.</p>
        <p>Form of claim. All claims shall be made in writing and shall be verified by the claimant or by his
               or her guardian, conservator, executor or administrator. No claim may be filed on
               behalf of a class of persons unless verified by every member of that class as required
               by this subdivision. In addition, all claims shall contain the information required
               by California Government Code Section 910.</p>
        <p>d.</p>
        <p>Claim prerequisite to suit. In accordance with California Government Code Sections 935(b) and 945.6, all claims
               shall be presented as provided in this section and acted upon by the city prior to
               the filing of any action on such claims and no such action may be maintained by a
               person who has not complied with the requirements of subdivisions b and c of this
               section.</p>
        <p>e.</p>
        <p>Suit. Any action brought against the city upon any claim or demand shall conform to the
               requirements of Sections 940 through 949 of the California Government Code. Any action
               brought against any employee of the city shall conform to the requirements of Sections
               950 and 951 of the California Government Code.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 12.06, 12/12/06.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
