<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-i/section-sec.-2.1">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Meetings of the city council—Time and place</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-i/section-sec.-2.1"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 2_1">
      <num>SEC. 2.1</num>
      <heading>Meetings of the city council—Time and place</heading>
      <content>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>Regularly scheduled meetings. Regular meetings of the city council shall be held on the second and fourth Tuesday
               of each month at the council chambers at the Mountain View Civic Center,
               
               500
               
               Castro Street, at 6:30 p.m. The council may conduct closed sessions pursuant to the
               Ralph M. Brown Act prior to the 6:30 p.m. start time for the open session agenda,
               provided that the time, place and subject of the closed session is shown on the council
               meeting agenda. Closed sessions may begin as early as 4:30 p.m. and shall be preceded
               by a brief open session to facilitate any announcement, report or comment as may be
               required by the Brown Act. Any meeting conducted by the council on the second and
               fourth Tuesday of the month which starts at a time different than 6:30 p.m. may be
               considered a regular meeting for all purposes provided that the meeting is noticed
               at least seventy-two (72) hours in advance, as required by the Ralph M. Brown Act
               for regular meeting notices.</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>Exception. The city council may from time to time, by resolution, change the time of a regular
               or special meeting or meetings as provided in subsection a. of this section for the
               purpose of facilitating the conservation of energy. If the council so elects, the
               resolution shall clearly state the duration of the change, or if no termination is
               stated, the earlier start time shall prevail until altered by a resolution of the
               city council.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 175.553, 7/13/59; Ord. No. 20.81, 10/26/81; Ord. No. 5.99, 4/13/99; Ord.
               No. 9.01, 6/12/01; Ord. No. 3.10, § 1, 2/9/10.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
