<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-3/article-ii/division-2/section-sec.-3.18.4">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Signs existing at the effective date of this division</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-3/article-ii/division-2/section-sec.-3.18.4"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 3_18_4">
      <num>SEC. 3.18.4</num>
      <heading>Signs existing at the effective date of this division</heading>
      <content>
        <p>Any sign lawfully existing at the effective date of this division, or lawfully existing
               hereafter upon the completion of any freeway, which sign is designed to have, or has,
               the advertising thereon to be viewed primarily from a freeway, or which does not otherwise
               conform to the provisions of this division shall be regarded as nonconforming and
               may be left in place; provided, however, that:</p>
        <p>(a)</p>
        <p>In the event that any such existing sign is determined by the director of public works,
                  the director of planning and the city building inspector to constitute a dangerous
                  or hazardous condition, the same shall be removed within thirty (30) days after written
                  notice to the owner of such sign, which notice shall be signed by such director of
                  public works, director of planning and city building inspector.</p>
        <p>(b)</p>
        <p>Any sign which is visible from any section of a freeway, and is designed to have,
                  or has, the advertising thereon maintained primarily to be viewed from such freeway,
                  shall be removed within one (1) year from the completion of such section of freeway,
                  or within three (3) years of the effective date of this division, whichever is sooner.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 175.622, 8/8/60.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
