<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-1/article-ii/section-sec.-1.26">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Failure to pay administrative penalties and costs</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-1/article-ii/section-sec.-1.26"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 1_26">
      <num>SEC. 1.26</num>
      <heading>Failure to pay administrative penalties and costs</heading>
      <content>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>Enforcement. Failure to pay the assessed administrative penalties and/or administrative costs
               specified in the administrative order may be enforced as a personal obligation of
               the violator, and/or if the violation is in connection with real property, a lien
               upon the real property, which shall remain in effect until all of the administrative
               penalties, interest and administrative costs are paid in full.</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>Late payment charges. Late payment charges shall accrue and are payable as specified in the schedule of
               administrative penalties.</p>
        <p>c.</p>
        <p>Notification of tax collector. The director of finance and administrative services shall notify the county tax collector
               of any administrative penalties and/or administrative costs imposed in connection
               with real property that have not been satisfied in full within ninety (90) days after
               the administrative order becomes final.</p>
        <p>d.</p>
        <p>Use of city water bill. With the written consent of the property owner, the director of finance and administrative
               services is authorized to include as a charge on any city water bill relating to the
               property any administrative penalties and/or administrative costs imposed in connection
               with real property that have not been satisfied in full within ninety (90) days after
               the administrative order becomes final.</p>
        <p>1.</p>
        <p>This option shall only be employed after notice to the named tenant and a determination
               by the enforcement officer or official that the violation was created by the tenant,
               not the landlord.</p>
        <p>2.</p>
        <p>The primary tenant on the property and/or the water service customer shall be served
               with written notice that the property owner has authorized this option at least thirty
               (30) days prior to the charge being attached to the water bill.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 12.02, 7/23/02.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
