<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-1/article-ii/section-sec.-1.22">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Hearing</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-1/article-ii/section-sec.-1.22"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 1_22">
      <num>SEC. 1.22</num>
      <heading>Hearing</heading>
      <content>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>Notice and time of hearing. Written notice of hearing shall be served on any person to whom the citation or compliance
               order was addressed and shall contain the date, time and place at which the hearing
               shall be conducted. The hearing shall be set for a date that is not less than fifteen
               (15) days and not more than sixty (60) days from the date of the notice of hearing.
               The hearing officer may approve a continuance of the hearing to any date for good
               cause.</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>Hearing procedure. At the hearing, the alleged violator shall have the opportunity to testify, present
               evidence, and to cross-examine witnesses concerning the administrative citation or
               compliance order. The alleged violator may appear personally or through an attorney.
               Prehearing discovery is not authorized. Subpoena of witnesses and documents shall
               be permitted as authorized by law. The hearing officer may conduct the hearing informally,
               both as to rules of procedure and admission of evidence, in any manner which will
               provide a fair hearing, and may continue the hearing to obtain additional evidence.
               The administrative citation or administrative compliance order and any additional
               report submitted by the enforcement officer, shall constitute presumptive evidence
               of the respective facts contained in those documents.</p>
        <p>c.</p>
        <p>Failure to appear. The failure of any alleged violator to appear at the hearing after proper notice
               or, in the alternative, to present written or demonstrative evidence shall constitute
               an admission of the violation by the alleged violator and an exhaustion of administrative
               remedies that may bar judicial review.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 12.02, 7/23/02.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
