<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-1/article-ii/section-sec.-1.23">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Administrative order</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-1/article-ii/section-sec.-1.23"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 1_23">
      <num>SEC. 1.23</num>
      <heading>Administrative order</heading>
      <content>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>Decision process. After considering all the testimony and evidence submitted at the hearing, the hearing
               officer shall issue a written administrative order, including findings regarding the
               existence of each violation and the extent of compliance, the reasons for that decision
               and notice of the right to judicial review, within thirty (30) days following completion
               of the hearing. The alleged violator shall be served with a copy of the administrative
               order within ten (10) calendar days following its issuance. The administrative order
               shall be final upon service on the violator, subject only to judicial review as allowed
               by law.</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>Penalty. If the hearing officer determines that the alleged violator committed the violation
               alleged by a preponderance of the evidence, the hearing officer shall establish an
               administrative penalty and a date the penalty and any administrative costs shall be
               due and payable. If the hearing officer finds that the administrative citation should
               not be sustained or that the amount of the administrative penalty should be reduced,
               the city shall refund the amount within thirty (30) days of the order.</p>
        <p>c.</p>
        <p>Administrative costs. The hearing officer may assess administrative costs against the violator from the
               date on which compliance was ordered. The administrative costs may include any and
               all costs incurred by the city in connection with the matter before the hearing officer,
               including, but not limited to, costs of inspection, investigation, staffing costs
               incurred in preparation for the hearing and for the hearing itself, and costs for
               all reinspections.</p>
        <p>d.</p>
        <p>Jurisdiction. After the administrative order becomes final, the hearing officer shall maintain
               continuing jurisdiction until full compliance is achieved and shall have the power
               to modify the administrative order, after providing the person subject to the administrative
               order with notice and an opportunity to be heard.</p>
        <p>1.</p>
        <p>Exception. The city attorney has independent jurisdiction to pursue alternate remedies
               for the same violations notwithstanding the pendency of the administrative proceedings
               pursuant to this article.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 12.02, 7/23/02.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
