<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-1/article-ii/section-sec.-1.29">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Administrative compliance order</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-1/article-ii/section-sec.-1.29"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 1_29">
      <num>SEC. 1.29</num>
      <heading>Administrative compliance order</heading>
      <content>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>Issuance. An enforcement official may issue a written compliance order, providing a reasonable
               time for correction of not less than ten (10) days, to any person responsible for
               a city code violation.</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>Contents of administrative compliance order. A compliance order issued pursuant to this article shall contain the following information:
               the date and location of the violation; the section of this code violated and a description
               of the violation; the action required to correct the violation; the time period after
               which administrative penalties will begin to accrue if compliance with the order has
               not been achieved; and the amount of penalties that will begin to accrue.</p>
        <p>c.</p>
        <p>Compliance and failure to comply. If the enforcement official determines that all violations have been corrected within
               the time specified in the compliance order or within any amended orders, the enforcement
               official shall so advise each party to whom the compliance order was addressed. If
               full compliance is not achieved within the time specified in the compliance order
               or within any amended orders, the enforcement official shall schedule a hearing before
               the hearing officer.</p>
        <p>d.</p>
        <p>Administrative order by hearing officer. If the hearing officer determines that a violation occurred which was not corrected
               within the time period specified in the compliance order, the hearing officer shall
               issue an administrative order which imposes any or all of the following: an order
               to correct code violations, including a schedule for correction, if appropriate; administrative
               penalties; and administrative costs as provided in this article.</p>
        <p>e.</p>
        <p>Administrative penalties. The hearing officer may impose administrative penalties for each day during which
               a violation occurs after compliance was ordered. Administrative penalties assessed
               by the hearing officer shall be due by the date specified in the administrative order.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 12.02, 7/23/02.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
