<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-1/article-ii/section-sec.-1.28">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Administrative citation</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-1/article-ii/section-sec.-1.28"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 1_28">
      <num>SEC. 1.28</num>
      <heading>Administrative citation</heading>
      <content>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>Issuance. An enforcement officer may issue an administrative citation to any person responsible
               for a city code violation. However, prior to the issuance of an administrative citation
               for a violation which pertains to building, plumbing, electrical or similar structural
               or zoning matters that do not create an immediate danger to health or safety, the
               enforcement officer shall provide a reasonable period to correct or otherwise remedy
               the violation of not less than ten (10) days.</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>Contents of administrative citation. Each administrative citation shall contain the following information: the date of
               the violation; the address or description of the location of the violation; the section
               or sections of this code violated and a description of the acts or omissions constituting
               the violation; the amount of the penalty for the code violation; a description of
               the penalty payment process, including a description of the time within which and
               the place to which the penalty shall be paid; a notice of right to a hearing, including
               the time within which the administrative citation may be contested, and how to request
               a hearing; and the name of the citing enforcement officer.</p>
        <p>c.</p>
        <p>Request for administrative citation hearing. Any recipient of an administrative citation may contest it before the hearing officer
               by requesting a hearing in writing and submitting the request and an advance deposit
               of the administrative penalty or a request for an advance deposit hardship waiver
               within thirty (30) calendar days from the date the administrative citation is served.</p>
        <p>d.</p>
        <p>Hardship waiver. Any person who requests a hearing to contest an administrative citation may request
               in writing an advance deposit hardship waiver, including the reasons for the request.
               The director of finance and administrative services may issue an advance deposit hardship
               waiver if he or she is satisfied that the person is unable to deposit the full amount
               of the penalty in advance of the hearing. The director shall issue a written determination
               of whether to issue the advance deposit hardship waiver. The written determination
               shall be final, subject only to judicial review as provided by law. If the director
               determines not to issue an advance deposit hardship waiver, the person shall remit
               the deposit to the city within ten (10) days of the date of that decision in order
               to secure the hearing.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 12.02, 7/23/02.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
