<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/part-i/article-vii/section-711">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Powers and duties of city attorney; eligibility, employment of attorneys to assist, etc., in legal matters</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/part-i/article-vii/section-711"
             temporalId="sSection 711">
      <num>Section 711</num>
      <heading>Powers and duties of city attorney; eligibility, employment of attorneys to assist, etc., in legal matters</heading>
      <content>
        <p>The city attorney shall have the power and be required to:</p>
        <p>(a)</p>
        <p>Represent and advise the council and all city officers in all matters of law pertaining
                  to their offices.</p>
        <p>(b)</p>
        <p>Represent and appear for the city in any or all actions and proceedings in which the
                  city is concerned or is a party; and represent and appear for any city officer or
                  employee or former city officer or employee for any action arising out of that person's
                  employment or by reason of that person's official capacity as may be required by law.</p>
        <p>(c)</p>
        <p>Attend all meetings of the council and give the city attorney's advice or opinion
                  in writing whenever requested to do so by the council or by any of the boards or officers
                  of the city.</p>
        <p>(d)</p>
        <p>Approve the form of all bonds given to and all contracts made by the city, endorsing
                  the city attorney's approval thereon in writing.</p>
        <p>(e)</p>
        <p>Prepare any and all proposed ordinances or resolutions for the city, and amendments
                  thereto.</p>
        <p>(f)</p>
        <p>Prosecute on behalf of the people all criminal cases for violation of this Charter
                  and of city ordinances.</p>
        <p>(g)</p>
        <p>Perform such other duties consistent with this Charter as may be required of the city
                  attorney by the council.</p>
        <p>(h)</p>
        <p>On vacating the office, surrender to his or her successor all books, papers, files
                  and documents pertaining to the city's affairs.</p>
        <p>To become eligible for appointment as a city attorney, the appointee shall have been
               admitted to practice as an attorney at law before the Supreme Court of the State of
               California, and shall have been engaged in the practice of law for at least three
               years immediately prior to that person's appointment.</p>
        <p>The council shall have control of all legal business and proceedings and may employ
               other attorneys to take charge of any litigation or matter or to assist the city attorney
               therein.</p>
        <p>(As amended June 3, 1980; November 3, 1998.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
