<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/part-i/article-vii/section-709">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Powers and duties of city clerk</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/part-i/article-vii/section-709"
             temporalId="sSection 709">
      <num>Section 709</num>
      <heading>Powers and duties of city clerk</heading>
      <content>
        <p>The city clerk shall have the power and be required to:</p>
        <p>(a)</p>
        <p>Attend all meetings of the council and be responsible for the recording and maintaining
                  of a full and true record of all the proceedings of the council in books that shall
                  bear appropriate titles and be devoted to such purpose.</p>
        <p>(b)</p>
        <p>Maintain separate books, in which shall be recorded respectively all ordinances and
                  resolutions, with the certificate of the clerk annexed to each thereof stating the
                  same to be the original or a correct copy and as to an ordinance requiring publication,
                  stating that the same has been published or posted in accordance with this Charter.</p>
        <p>(c)</p>
        <p>Maintain separate books, in which a record shall be made of all written contracts
                  and official bonds.</p>
        <p>(d)</p>
        <p>Keep all aforementioned books properly indexed and open to public inspection when
                  not in actual use.</p>
        <p>(e)</p>
        <p>Be the custodian of the seal of the city.</p>
        <p>(f)</p>
        <p>Administer oaths or affirmations, take affidavits and depositions pertaining to the
                  affairs and business of the city and certify copies of the official records.</p>
        <p>(g)</p>
        <p>Have charge of all city elections.</p>
        <p>(h)</p>
        <p>Perform such other duties consistent with this Charter as may be required of the city
                  clerk by the council.</p>
        <p>(As amended June 3, 1980.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
