<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/part-i/article-vii/section-702">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Administrative departments</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/part-i/article-vii/section-702"
             temporalId="sSection 702">
      <num>Section 702</num>
      <heading>Administrative departments</heading>
      <content>
        <p>The council may provide by ordinance not inconsistent with this Charter for the organization,
               conduct and operation of the several offices and departments of the city as established
               by this Charter, for the creation of additional departments, divisions, offices and
               agencies and for their alteration or abolition. It may further provide by ordinance
               or resolution for the assignment and reassignment of divisions, offices and agencies
               to departments, and for the number, titles, qualifications, powers, duties, and compensation
               for all officers and employees, consistent with this Charter.</p>
        <p>Each department so created shall be headed by an officer as department head who shall
               be appointed by the city manager, except as otherwise provided by this Charter.</p>
        <p>When the positions are not incompatible, the council may combine in one person the
               powers and duties of two or more offices.</p>
        <p>The council may transfer or consolidate functions of the city government to or with
               appropriate functions of the state or county government, or may make use of such functions
               of the state or county government, and in case of any such transfer or consolidation
               the provisions of the Charter providing for the function of the city government so
               transferred or consolidated shall be deemed suspended during the continuance of such
               transfer or consolidation to the extent that such suspension is made necessary or
               convenient and is set forth in the ordinance or resolution establishing such transfer
               or consolidation. Any such transfer of consolidation may be repealed in like manner.</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
