<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-iv/division-1/section-sec.-2.69.2">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Acceptance of state aid for selection and training of public safety communicators</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-iv/division-1/section-sec.-2.69.2"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 2_69_2">
      <num>SEC. 2.69.2</num>
      <heading>Acceptance of state aid for selection and training of public safety communicators</heading>
      <content>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>The City of Mountain View declares that it desires to qualify to receive aid from
               the State of California under the provisions of Sections 13522 and 13525, Chapter
               1, of Title 4, Part 4, of the California Penal Code.</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>Pursuant to Section 13510(c) of the California Penal Code, the City of Mountain View
               will adhere to standards for recruitment and training of public safety communicators
               established by the California Commission on Peace Officer Standards and Training (POST).</p>
        <p>c.</p>
        <p>Pursuant to Section 13512 of the California Penal Code, the commission and its representatives
               may make such inquiries as deemed appropriate by the commission to ascertain that
               the City of Mountain View's public communicator personnel adhere to standards for
               selection and training established by the Commission on Peace Officer Standards and
               Training (POST).</p>
        <p>d.</p>
        <p>For the purposes of this section, public safety communicator shall be defined to include
               nonpeace officer personnel employed full-time or part-time by the city to perform
               duties which include as a primary responsibility receiving emergency calls for law
               enforcement services and/or dispatching law enforcement personnel.</p>
        <p>(Ord. 22.90, 11/27/90.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
