<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-xii/division-4/section-sec-2.160">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Electronic filing of campaign statements and statements of economic interests</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-xii/division-4/section-sec-2.160"
             temporalId="sSEC 2_160">
      <num>SEC 2.160</num>
      <heading>Electronic filing of campaign statements and statements of economic interests</heading>
      <content>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>Any elected officer, candidate, committee or other person required to file statements,
               reports or other documents required by Chapter 4 (commencing with Section 84100 of
               the Government Code), except an elected officer, candidate, committee or other person
               who received contributions totaling less than one thousand dollars ($1,000), and makes
               expenditures totaling less than one thousand dollars ($1,000), in a calendar year
               shall file those statements, reports or other documents online or electronically with
               the city clerk. This section also requires online or electronic filing of statement
               of economic interest reports (form 700) by any person holding a position listed in
               Government Code Section 82700.</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>In any instance in which an original statement, report or other document must be filed
               with the California Secretary of State and a copy of that statement, report or other
               document is required to be filed with the city clerk, the filer may, but is not required
               to, file the copy electronically.</p>
        <p>c.</p>
        <p>If the city clerk's electronic system is not capable of accepting a particular type
               of statement, report or other document, an elected officer, candidate, committee or
               other person shall file that document with the city clerk in an alternative format.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 16.16, § 3, 11/22/16.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
