<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-xii/division-6/section-sec.-2.183">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Penalties</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-xii/division-6/section-sec.-2.183"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 2_183">
      <num>SEC. 2.183</num>
      <heading>Penalties</heading>
      <content>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>Criminal enforcement. Any person who knowingly, willfully or negligently violates any provisions of this
               division is guilty of a misdemeanor. Any person who causes any other person to violate
               any provision of this division, or who aids and abets any other person in the violation
               of any provision of this division, shall be liable under the provisions of this division.
               Any monetary penalty for such a violation shall be the maximum amount permitted by
               law.</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>Civil enforcement.</p>
        <p>1.</p>
        <p>Any person who intentionally or negligently violates any provision of this division
               shall be liable in a civil action brought by the city attorney. Where no specific
               civil penalty is provided, a person may be liable for an amount up to ten thousand
               dollars ($10,000.00) for each violation. Upon collection, said sum shall be deposited
               into the general fund of the city.</p>
        <p>2.</p>
        <p>Injunctive relief. The city attorney, or a person residing within the city, may bring
               an action for injunction relief to enjoin violations or to compel compliance with
               the provision of this division if the city attorney declines to file such an action.</p>
        <p>3.</p>
        <p>A person other than the city attorney may bring a civil action for violations under
               this division if the city attorney declines to file a civil action. If a judgment
               is entered against the defendant(s) in an action, a private plaintiff shall receive
               fifty (50) percent of the amount recovered. The remaining fifty (50) percent shall
               be deposited into the city's general fund.</p>
        <p>4.</p>
        <p>If two (2) or more persons are responsible for any violation, they shall be jointly
               and severally liable.</p>
        <p>5.</p>
        <p>In determining the amount of liability under this subsection, the court may take into
               account any mitigating factors and any aggravating factors.</p>
        <p>6.</p>
        <p>No civil action alleging a violation of this division shall commence more than two
               (2) years after the date of the election for which the funds at issue were contributed
               or expended.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 5.22, § 7, 4/26/22.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
