<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-1/article-i/section-sec.-1.2">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Definitions and rules of construction</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-1/article-i/section-sec.-1.2"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 1_2">
      <num>SEC. 1.2</num>
      <heading>Definitions and rules of construction</heading>
      <content>
        <p>In the construction of this code and of all ordinances of the city, the following
               rules shall be observed, unless such construction would be inconsistent with the manifest
               intent of the city council or the context clearly requires otherwise:</p>
        <p>City. The words &quot;the city&quot; or &quot;this city&quot; shall be construed as if followed by the
               words &quot;of Mountain View.&quot;</p>
        <p>Code. The words &quot;the code&quot; or &quot;this code&quot; shall mean &quot;The Code of the City of Mountain
               View, California.&quot;</p>
        <p>Computation of time. The time period during which any act provided by this code is
               to be done is computed by excluding the first day and including the last day, unless
               the last day is a holiday, in which case such period shall be extended to the first
               day which is not a holiday.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 19.66, 8/8/66.)</p>
        <p>Council. Whenever the word &quot;council&quot; is used in this code, it shall be construed to
               mean the city council of the City of Mountain View.</p>
        <p>County. The words &quot;the county&quot; or &quot;this county&quot; shall mean the County of Santa Clara.</p>
        <p>Day.* A day is the period of time between any midnight and the midnight following.</p>
        <p>* For similar state law, see Gov. C.A., Sec. 6806.</p>
        <p>Daytime, nighttime.* &quot;Daytime&quot; is the period of time between sunrise and sunset. &quot;Nighttime&quot;
               is the period of time between sunset and sunrise.</p>
        <p>* For similar state law, see Gov. C.A., Sec. 6807.</p>
        <p>Gender.* The masculine gender includes the feminine and neuter.</p>
        <p>* For similar state law, see Gov. C.A., Sec. 12.</p>
        <p>Holiday. Every Saturday and Sunday; January 1st, known as New Year's Day; the third
               Monday in January, known as Martin Luther King Jr. Day; the third Monday in February,
               known as President's Day; March 31st, known as Cesar Chavez Day; the last Monday in
               May, known as Memorial Day; June 19th, known as Juneteenth; July 4th, known as Independence
               Day; the first Monday in September, known as Labor Day; September 9th, known as Admission
               Day; November 11th, known as Veterans' Day; the fourth Thursday in November, known
               as Thanksgiving Day; the Friday following Thanksgiving Day; December 25th, known as
               Christmas Day; and every day appointed by the President of the United States, the
               Governor of California, or the City Council or their designee. Should any of the above-listed
               holidays fall on a Saturday, the preceding Friday shall be deemed a holiday, and should
               any of the above-listed holidays fall on Sunday, the following Monday shall be deemed
               a holiday.</p>
        <p>In the city. The words &quot;in the city&quot; shall mean and include all territory over which
               the city now has, or shall hereafter acquire jurisdiction for the exercise of its
               police powers or other regulatory powers.</p>
        <p>Joint authority.* All words giving a joint authority to three (3) or more persons
               or officers shall be construed as giving such authority to a majority of such persons
               or officers.</p>
        <p>* See C. C., Sec. 12.</p>
        <p>Month.* The word &quot;month&quot; shall mean a calendar month.</p>
        <p>* For similar state law, see Gov. C.A., Sec. 6804.</p>
        <p>Number.* The singular number includes the plural, and the plural the singular.</p>
        <p>* For similar state law, see Gov. C. A., Sec. 13.</p>
        <p>Oath.* &quot;Oath&quot; includes an affirmation.</p>
        <p>* For similar state law, see Gov. C. A., Sec. 15.</p>
        <p>Officers, departments, etc. Officers, departments, boards, commissions and employees
               referred to in this code shall mean officers, departments, boards, commissions and
               employees of the City of Mountain View, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise.</p>
        <p>Official time. Whenever certain hours are named in this code, they shall mean Pacific
               Standard Time or Daylight Saving Time, as may be in current use in the city.</p>
        <p>Or, and. &quot;Or&quot; may be read &quot;and,&quot; and &quot;and&quot; may be read &quot;or,&quot; if the sense requires
               it.</p>
        <p>Owner. The word &quot;owner,&quot; applied to a building or land, shall include any part owner,
               joint owner, tenant in common, tenant in partnership, joint tenant or tenant by the
               entirety of the whole or of a part of such building or land.</p>
        <p>Person.* &quot;Person&quot; includes any person, firm, association, organization, partnership,
               business trust, corporation or company, and, where applicable shall include the United
               States, the State of California, and any public corporation, political subdivision,
               city, county, district, or any agency thereof.</p>
        <p>* For similar state law, see Gov. C. A., Sec. 17; C.C.P., Sec. 17.</p>
        <p>Personal property.* &quot;Personal property&quot; includes every species of property, except
               real property as defined in this section.</p>
        <p>* See C. C., Sec. 14, 663.</p>
        <p>Preceding, following. The words &quot;preceding&quot; and &quot;following&quot; mean next before and next
               after, respectively.</p>
        <p>Process.* &quot;Process&quot; includes a writ or summons issued in the course of judicial proceedings
               of either a civil or criminal nature.</p>
        <p>* For similar state law, see Gov. C. A., Sec. 22.</p>
        <p>Property.* The word &quot;property&quot; shall include real and personal property.</p>
        <p>* See C. C., Sec. 14; C. C. P., Sec. 17.</p>
        <p>Real property.* &quot;Real property&quot; shall include lands, tenements and hereditaments.</p>
        <p>* See C. C., Sec. 14, 658.</p>
        <p>Shall, may.* &quot;Shall&quot; is mandatory and &quot;may&quot; is permissive.</p>
        <p>* For similar state law, see Gov. C. A., Sec. 14.</p>
        <p>Signature or subscription by mark.* &quot;Signature&quot; or &quot;subscription&quot; includes a mark
               when the signer or subscriber cannot write, such signer's or subscriber's name being
               written near the mark by a witness who writes his own name near the signer's or subscriber's
               name; but, a signature or subscription by mark can be acknowledged or can serve as
               a signature or subscription to a sworn statement only when two witnesses so sign their
               own names thereto.</p>
        <p>* For similar state law, see Gov. C.A., Sec. 16.</p>
        <p>State. The words &quot;the state&quot; or &quot;this state&quot; shall be construed to mean the State
               of California.</p>
        <p>Tenant or occupant. The words &quot;tenant&quot; or &quot;occupant&quot; applied to a building or land,
               shall include any person holding a written or an oral lease of, or who occupies the
               whole or a part of such building or land, either alone or with others.</p>
        <p>Tenses.* The present tense includes the past and future tenses, and the future includes
               the present.</p>
        <p>* For similar state law, see Gov. C. A., Sec. 11.</p>
        <p>Week.* A &quot;week&quot; consists of seven (7) consecutive days.</p>
        <p>* For similar state law, see Gov. C. A., Sec. 6805.</p>
        <p>Writing.* &quot;Writing&quot; includes any form of recorded message capable of comprehension
               by ordinary visual means. Whenever any notice, report, statement or record is required
               or authorized by this Code, it shall be made in writing in the English language, unless
               it is expressly provided otherwise.</p>
        <p>* For similar state law, see Gov. C. A., Sec. 8.</p>
        <p>Year.* The word &quot;year&quot; shall mean a calendar year, except where otherwise provided.</p>
        <p>* For state law definition of &quot;year&quot;, see Gov. C. A., Sec. 6803.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 19.66, 8/8/66; Ord. No. 6.71, 2/8/71; Ord. No. 29.74, 8/26/74; Ord. No. 7.2024, § 1(Exh. A), 10/22/24.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
