<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-xii/division-1/section-sec.-2.102">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Campaign disclosure reports</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-xii/division-1/section-sec.-2.102"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 2_102">
      <num>SEC. 2.102</num>
      <heading>Campaign disclosure reports</heading>
      <content>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>All candidates, office holders and candidate-controlled committees or committees primarily
               formed to support or oppose a candidate(s) for the city council or the qualification
               or passage of a local ballot measure(s) participating in municipal elections that
               are required to file campaign disclosure reports under the Political Reform Act, Government
               Code 81000, et seq., shall also file said disclosure reports with the city clerk's
               office on the same date the filing is required by state law. The name of candidates
               and committees with a direct link to the campaign reports submitted by each candidate
               or committee shall be available on the city's website within five (5) business days
               from the date of receipt of the reports by the city clerk. A final disclosure report
               shall be filed as required by Sec. 2.104b.</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>Noncandidate groups, individuals and candidate-controlled committees or committees
               primarily formed to support or oppose a candidate(s) for the city council or the qualification
               or passage of a local ballot measure(s) participating in municipal election that are
               required to file campaign disclosure forms pursuant to state law shall also file all
               forms required by this division. Participation in the election shall occur on the
               date the noncandidate group, individual or committee accepts contributions, makes
               expenditures or contracts to make an expenditure in an amount(s) which requires the
               filing of campaign statements under state law.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 8.16, § 1, 6/14/16; Ord. No. 16.16, § 2, 11/22/16.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
