<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-xii/division-3/section-sec.-2.152">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Penalties/reimbursement</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-xii/division-3/section-sec.-2.152"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 2_152">
      <num>SEC. 2.152</num>
      <heading>Penalties/reimbursement</heading>
      <content>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>Any violation of the voluntary expenditure limit shall, within seventy-two (72) hours
               of the city's knowledge of the violation, be:</p>
        <p>1.</p>
        <p>Forwarded to a newspaper of general circulation for publication;</p>
        <p>2.</p>
        <p>Posted on the city's website; and</p>
        <p>3.</p>
        <p>Posted at a reasonably accessible location at city hall.</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>If the city contributed public funds to offset the costs of a candidate's candidate
               statement fee or the candidate violates the voluntary expenditure limit which they
               previously elected, the candidate or councilmember-elect shall repay to the city the
               entire city contribution as required by this section.</p>
        <p>1.</p>
        <p>Partial repayment. If a candidate exceeds the voluntary expenditure limit by no more
               than five hundred dollars ($500), the candidate shall repay to the city twenty-five
               (25) percent of the amount the city paid toward the candidate statement fee.</p>
        <p>2.</p>
        <p>Full repayment. If the candidate exceeds the voluntary expenditure limit by more than
               five hundred dollars ($500), the candidate shall repay to the city the entire amount
               of the city contribution.</p>
        <p>c.</p>
        <p>In all cases where the candidate has accepted a partial city contribution to the cost
               of the candidate statement fee, it is up to the applicant to determine compliance
               with this section, and if repayment is required by this section, the repayment is
               due and payable to the city within thirty (30) days of the expenditure that placed
               the candidate over the voluntary expenditure limit. The obligation to repay is not
               contingent on the receipt of an invoice from the city. For each month the candidate
               remains delinquent in the repayment past the initial thirty-day period, interest shall
               accrue on any delinquency at the rate of ten (10) percent per annum.</p>
        <p>d.</p>
        <p>Methods of collection. In addition to all other remedies available to the city at
               law, the city auditor is directed to deduct any delinquent amounts on a month-to-month
               basis until paid in full from any councilmember-elect's city paycheck until the delinquency
               is paid in full. In the event of an unsuccessful candidate, the city clerk is directed
               not to accept nomination papers for a future election until any delinquency from a
               prior election is paid in full, including interest.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 3.04, 5/25/04; Ord. No. 4.06, 4/25/06; Ord. No. 8.16, § 1, 6/14/16.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
