<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-xiii/section-sec.-2.207">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Bidding—Formal process</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-xiii/section-sec.-2.207"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 2_207">
      <num>SEC. 2.207</num>
      <heading>Bidding—Formal process</heading>
      <content>
        <p>When the estimated cost of individual purchases of supplies, materials, equipment
               and certain services, and the estimated return from all individual sales of property,
               real or personal, exceeds the limit set forth in California Public Contract Code at
               Section 22032(b), or any successor provision authorizing public agencies to let contracts
               by informal procurement procedures, the following formal bidding procedures shall
               be followed:</p>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>Notice inviting sealed bids. Notices inviting sealed bids shall be prepared and shall include a general description
                  (&quot;specifications&quot;) of the supplies, materials, equipment or services to be purchased
                  or sold, shall state where bid forms and specifications may be secured and the time
                  and place for opening bids.</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>Publication of notice. The notice inviting sealed bids shall be published at least seven (7) days before
                  the date of opening of bids. Notice shall be published at least once in an official
                  newspaper of general circulation in the city or, as an alternative method of publication,
                  it shall be posted in at least three (3) public places in the city that have been
                  designated by ordinances as the places for posting public notices. At the discretion
                  of the purchasing agent, bid invitations may be transmitted electronically to appropriate
                  vendors.</p>
        <p>c.</p>
        <p>Bidders' list. The purchasing agent shall solicit bids from all responsible prospective suppliers
                  who have requested their names to be added to a bidders' list, which the purchasing
                  agent shall maintain, by sending them such notice as will acquaint them with the proposed
                  purchase or sale. In any case, invitations sent to the vendors on the bidders' list
                  shall be limited to commodities that are similar in character to the commodities ordinarily
                  available from proposed vendor to which the invitations are sent.</p>
        <p>d.</p>
        <p>Bidder's security. When it is deemed necessary by the purchasing agent, bidder's security may be prescribed
                  in the public notices inviting bids. When required, security shall be in the following
                  form: either a certified or cashier's check or a bidder's bond executed by a corporate
                  surety authorized to engage in such business in the state, made payable to the city.
                  Such security shall be in an amount not less than that specified in the notice inviting
                  bids or in the specifications referred to therein or, if no amount is specified by
                  the notice inviting bids, then in an amount not less than ten (10) percent of the
                  aggregate amount of the bid. Bidders shall be entitled to return of their bid security.
                  A successful bidder shall forfeit any surety required by the purchasing agent upon
                  failure on the bidder's part to enter into a contract within fifteen (15) days after
                  the award of the contract has been transmitted by any method authorized by law.</p>
        <p>e.</p>
        <p>Bid opening procedure. Sealed bids shall be submitted to the purchasing agent and shall be identified in
                  accordance with instructions to bidders. Bids shall be opened in public at the time
                  and place stated in the public notices. When no member of the public is in attendance
                  at bid opening, at least one (1) city employee, in addition to the city employee opening
                  the bids, will be present. A tabulation of all bids received shall be open for public
                  inspection.</p>
        <p>f.</p>
        <p>Rejection of bids. At the city manager's discretion, the city manager or designee may reject any and
                  all bids presented and readvertise for bids; or may waive any informalities or minor
                  irregularities in a bid.</p>
        <p>g.</p>
        <p>Award of contract. Contracts shall be awarded by the city manager or designee to the lowest responsive
                  and responsible bidder on purchases and the highest responsible bidder on sales, except
                  as otherwise provided herein. Should the successful bidder refuse or fail to enter
                  into an agreement with the city, the city manager or designee may execute the contract
                  with the next lowest responsive and responsible bidder.</p>
        <p>h.</p>
        <p>Tie bids.</p>
        <p>1.</p>
        <p>If two (2) or more bids are received for the same total amount, unit price, quality
                  and service being equal, the contract shall be awarded to the lowest local bidder
                  in the case of purchases and highest local bidder in the case of sales;</p>
        <p>2.</p>
        <p>Where no local bidder is involved, the purchasing agent shall award the contract to
                  one (1) of the bidders by drawing lots in public.</p>
        <p>i.</p>
        <p>Performance bonds. The purchasing agent shall have the authority to require a performance bond before
                  entering into a contract in such amount as the purchasing agent shall find reasonably
                  necessary to protect the best interests of the city. Such surety may be in the form
                  of a certified or cashier's check, corporate surety bond or savings and loan certificate.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 7.16, § 1, 5/24/16; Ord. No. 5.2025, § 4, 6/24/25.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
