<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-xiii/section-sec.-2.200">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Public works projects—Alternate bidding procedures</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-xiii/section-sec.-2.200"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 2_200">
      <num>SEC. 2.200</num>
      <heading>Public works projects—Alternate bidding procedures</heading>
      <content>
        <p>When the estimated construction cost of a public works project has a construction
               value not in excess of the limit set forth in California Public Contract Code at Section
               22034, the project may be bid and awarded through the following alternate bidding
               procedures as authorized by City Charter Section 1107.</p>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>Prospective bidders' list. The city shall maintain a list of qualified contractors, identified according to
                  categories of work. Minimum criteria for development and maintenance of the contractors
                  list shall be determined by the public works director or designee.</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>Notice inviting informal bids. A notice inviting informal bids shall describe the project in general terms and how
                  to obtain more detailed information about the project, and shall be mailed to all
                  contractors on the list of qualified contractors for the category of the work to be
                  competitively bid. Although not required, a notice inviting bids may be posted in
                  trade journals, on-line construction exchange services, on the city website, and advertised.
                  All notices inviting bids shall be mailed not less than ten (10) calendar days before
                  bids are due. The notice shall include when the bids are due and the time and place
                  for submission of the bids.</p>
        <p>c.</p>
        <p>Bid openings. All bids shall be opened either:</p>
        <p>(1)</p>
        <p>Via an electronic procurement system; or</p>
        <p>(2)</p>
        <p>In the presence of any City officer who takes no part in inviting bids, the contract
                  award process, or overseeing the performance of the contract being bid.</p>
        <p>d.</p>
        <p>Award of contract. The public works director or designee may award the contract to the lowest responsible
                  bidder. The public works director or designee may reject any and all bids presented
                  and may readvertise the project. Upon acceptance of the job, the awarded bidder must
                  provide and maintain an insurance certificate, bonds, an active contractor's license
                  and obtain a city business license to the satisfaction of the public works director
                  or designee. In the event the awarded bidder fails to provide the required documentation
                  in a timely manner and to the satisfaction of the public works director or designee,
                  the next lowest responsible bidder may be awarded the contract.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 7.16, § 1, 5/24/16; Ord. No. 5.2025, § 1, 6/24/25.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
