<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-xiii/section-sec.-2.204">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Powers and duties of purchasing agent</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-xiii/section-sec.-2.204"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 2_204">
      <num>SEC. 2.204</num>
      <heading>Powers and duties of purchasing agent</heading>
      <content>
        <p>The purchasing agent shall have power and be required to:</p>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>Procure all supplies, materials, equipment and certain services required by any department,
                  office or agency of the city government; and dispose of all property, real or personal,
                  in accordance with rules and regulations as prescribed by this article and such purchasing
                  procedures as the purchasing agent shall adopt for the internal management and operation
                  of the purchasing section. &quot;Certain services&quot; shall include, but not be limited to,
                  professional and specialized services provided with the acquisition of supplies, materials,
                  and equipment in order to place them into service. Such purchasing procedures adopted
                  by the purchasing agent shall not be effective until approved by the city manager;</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>Within a specified delivery period, procure for the city supplies, materials, equipment
                  and certain services at the least expense to the city for the quality needed, taking
                  full advantage of trade and cash discounts and all tax exemptions to which the city
                  may be entitled;</p>
        <p>c.</p>
        <p>Specify proper standard nomenclature for supplies, materials and equipment required
                  by any department, office or agency of the city government;</p>
        <p>d.</p>
        <p>Prepare and maintain standard suggested specifications for materials, supplies and
                  equipment whenever practicable;</p>
        <p>e.</p>
        <p>Maintain a record of all sources of supply of goods or services;</p>
        <p>f.</p>
        <p>Declare vendors who default on their quotations irresponsible bidders and disqualify
                  them from receiving any business from the city for a stated period of time after notification
                  to the city manager;</p>
        <p>g.</p>
        <p>Prescribe by regulation the procedure under which emergency purchases falling within
                  this article may be made by department heads;</p>
        <p>h.</p>
        <p>Require when necessary sufficient tests of samples submitted with bids and samples
                  of deliveries when necessary to determine their quality and conformance with the specifications;</p>
        <p>i.</p>
        <p>At the discretion of the purchasing agent, delegate authority to staff outside of
                  purchasing for the procurement of goods or services up to twenty thousand dollars
                  ($20,000);</p>
        <p>j.</p>
        <p>Improve the efficiency and effectiveness of the procurement process whenever possible
                  by all available means, including the use of available technology.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 7.16, § 1, 5/24/16; Ord. No. 5.17, § 2, 10/24/17; Ord. No. 5.2025, § 3, 6/24/25.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
