<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-3/article-i/section-sec.-3.1">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Definitions</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-3/article-i/section-sec.-3.1"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 3_1">
      <num>SEC. 3.1</num>
      <heading>Definitions</heading>
      <content>
        <p>For the purposes of this article, the following words and phrases shall have the meanings
               respectively ascribed to them by this section:</p>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>Commercial handbill. &quot;Commercial handbill&quot; shall mean and include any printed or written
                  matter, any sample or device, dodger, circular, leaflet, pamphlet, paper, booklet,
                  or any other printed or otherwise reproduced original or copies of any matter or literature:</p>
        <p>1.</p>
        <p>Which advertises for sale any merchandise, product, commodity, or thing; or</p>
        <p>2.</p>
        <p>Which directs attention to any business or mercantile or commercial establishment,
                  or other activity, for the purpose of either directly or indirectly promoting the
                  interests thereof by sales; or</p>
        <p>3.</p>
        <p>Which directs attention to or advertises any meeting, theatrical performance, exhibition,
                  or event of any kind, for which an admission fee is charged for the purpose of private
                  gain or profit. The terms of this clause shall not apply where an admission fee is
                  charged or a collection is taken up for the purpose of defraying the expenses incident
                  to such meeting, theatrical performance, exhibition, or event of any kind, when either
                  of the same is held, given, or takes place in connection with the dissemination of
                  information which is not restricted under the ordinary rules of decency, good morals,
                  public peace, safety and good order; provided, that nothing contained in this clause
                  shall be deemed to authorize the holding, giving or taking place of any meeting, theatrical
                  performance, exhibition, or event of any kind without a license where such license
                  is or may be required by any law of the state, or under any ordinance of the city;
                  or</p>
        <p>4.</p>
        <p>Which, while containing reading matter other than advertising matter, is predominantly
                  and essentially an advertisement, and is distributed or circulated for advertising
                  purposes, or for the private benefit and gain of any person so engaged as advertiser
                  or distributor.</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>Handbill distributor. &quot;Handbill distributor&quot; shall mean and include any person engaging
                  or engaged in the business for hire or gain of distributing commercial or noncommercial
                  handbills, other than newspapers distributed to subscribers thereof, and any person
                  receiving compensation directly or indirectly for the distribution of such handbills.</p>
        <p>c.</p>
        <p>Newspaper. &quot;Newspaper&quot; shall mean and include any newspaper:</p>
        <p>1.</p>
        <p>Which has for its principal purpose the dissemination of local or telegraphic news
                  and intelligence of a general character;</p>
        <p>2.</p>
        <p>Which is printed and published at regular intervals;</p>
        <p>3.</p>
        <p>Which has a bona fide subscription list of paying subscribers within the city and
                  is principally distributed only to paying subscribers;</p>
        <p>4.</p>
        <p>Which is not distributed or circulated primarily for advertising purposes;</p>
        <p>5.</p>
        <p>In addition thereto, shall mean and include any periodical or current magazine regularly
                  published with not less than four (4) issues per year and sold to the public.</p>
        <p>d.</p>
        <p>Noncommercial handbill. &quot;Noncommercial handbill&quot; shall mean and include any printed
                  or written matter, any sample or device, dodger, circular, leaflet, pamphlet, newspaper,
                  magazine, paper booklet or any other printed or otherwise reproduced original or copies
                  of any matter or literature not included in the definitions of a commercial handbill
                  or a newspaper.</p>
        <p>e.</p>
        <p>Private premises. &quot;Private premises&quot; shall mean and include any dwelling, house, building,
                  or other structure, whether inhabited or temporarily or continuously uninhabited or
                  vacant, and shall include any yard, grounds, walk, driveway, porch, steps, vestibule,
                  hallway, or mailbox belonging or appurtenant to such dwelling, house, building, or
                  other structure, and any vacant lot or other private property.</p>
        <p>f.</p>
        <p>Public place. &quot;Public place&quot; shall mean and include any and all streets, boulevards,
                  avenues, lanes, alleys, or other public ways, and any and all public parks, squares,
                  spaces, plazas, grounds and buildings.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 175.481, 6/30/58.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
