<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-xii/division-2/section-sec.-2.105">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Definitions</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-xii/division-2/section-sec.-2.105"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 2_105">
      <num>SEC. 2.105</num>
      <heading>Definitions</heading>
      <content>
        <p>The definitions set forth in the Political Reform Act of 1974 as amended (Government
               Code Section 82000 et seq.) shall govern the interpretation of this division, unless
               otherwise specified herein.</p>
        <p>&quot;Advertisement&quot; means any general or public communication which is authorized and
               paid for by a committee for the purpose of supporting or opposing a candidate(s) for
               municipal elective office or a municipal ballot measure(s). A communication that expressly
               advocates for or against a clearly identified municipal candidate(s) or measure(s),
               as defined in Government Code Section 82025, supports or opposes a candidate(s) for
               municipal elective office or a municipal ballot measure(s). Advertisement excludes
               communications paid for by a candidate or candidate-controlled committee established
               for elective office for the controlling candidate and communications from an organization
               to its members other than a communication from a political party to its members. Advertisement
               includes print and written advertisements, including mass mailings (as defined in
               Government Code Section 82041.5 and includes email), newspaper ads, and flyers. This
               division does not apply to small promotional items such as pens, pencils, mugs, clothing,
               skywriting or other items where the required disclosures are impracticable or cannot
               be reasonably printed or displayed in an easily legible typeface. This division does
               not apply to video or audio advertisements.</p>
        <p>&quot;Candidate&quot; means a candidate for city council.</p>
        <p>&quot;Committee&quot; means the same as set forth by California Government Code Section 82013,
               and as may be amended from time to time.</p>
        <p>&quot;Contribution&quot; means the same as set forth by California Government Code Section 82015,
               and Title 2 of the CCR, Section 18215, and in addition includes an enforceable promise
               to make a payment by a donor to a committee placing an advertisement when made subject
               to a condition, agreement or understanding with the committee that all or a portion
               would be used to pay for the advertisement.</p>
        <p>&quot;Cumulative contribution&quot; means the cumulative amount of contributions received by
               a committee beginning six (6) months before the date of the expenditure and ending
               seven (7) days before the time the advertisement is sent to the printer.</p>
        <p>&quot;Earmarked funds&quot; means any of the following:</p>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>The contributor solicited and received the funds from donors for the purpose of making
                  a contribution to the committee paying for the advertisement.</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>The funds were given to the contributor subject to a condition, agreement or understanding
                  with the donor that all or a portion would be used to make a contribution to the committee
                  paying for the advertisement, including the identification of the committee as a potential
                  recipient.</p>
        <p>c.</p>
        <p>The contributor had existing funds from a donor and a subsequent agreement or understanding
                  was reached with the donor that all or a portion of the funds would be used to contribute
                  to the committee paying for the advertisement, including the identification of the
                  committee as a potential recipient.</p>
        <p>d.</p>
        <p>The funds were promised, subject to an enforceable promise, to the contributor subject
                  to a condition, agreement or understanding with the donor that all or a portion would
                  be used to make a contribution to the committee paying for the advertisement, including
                  the identification of the committee as a potential recipient.</p>
        <p>&quot;Top contributors&quot; means the persons from whom the committee paying for an advertisement
               has received its five (5) highest cumulative contributions of two thousand five hundred
               dollars ($2,500.00) or more.</p>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>If two (2) or more contributors of identical amounts qualify as top contributors,
                  the most recent contributor shall be listed before any other top contributor of the
                  same amount in any disclosure required by this article.</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>If a contributor appears to qualify as a top contributor but received earmarked funds
                  to make the contribution, the person, entity or committee that earmarked the funds
                  and gave the funds to the contributor shall instead be disclosed as the top contributor.
                  The person, entity or committee that transferred earmarked funds shall disclose the
                  true source of the funds to the committee receiving the earmarked funds at the time
                  the funds are promised or transferred.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 8.16, § 1, 6/14/16; Ord. No. 6.18, § 2, 4/24/18; Ord. No. 10.22, § 1, 6/28/22.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
