<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lawDoc xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0"
        identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-xii/division-2/section-sec.-2.106">
  <meta>
    <dc:title>Disclosure on advertisements, generally</dc:title>
  </meta>
  <main>
    <section identifier="/ca-mountain-view/chapter-2/article-xii/division-2/section-sec.-2.106"
             temporalId="sSEC_ 2_106">
      <num>SEC. 2.106</num>
      <heading>Disclosure on advertisements, generally</heading>
      <content>
        <p>a.</p>
        <p>In addition to required disclosures under the Political Reform Act, an advertisement
               paid for by a committee must disclose the top contributors. Any advertisement paid
               for by a committee, following the identification of the committee as required under
               the Political Reform Act, shall disclose the names of the top contributors to the
               committee paying for the advertisement. If fewer than five (5) contributors qualify
               as top contributors, only those contributors that qualify shall be disclosed pursuant
               to this section. If no contributors qualify as top contributors, this disclosure is
               not required. The disclosure shall read: &quot;Major funding by (name and occupation or
               business interest),&quot; identifying the top contributors to the committee paying for
               the advertisement.</p>
        <p>b.</p>
        <p>Notwithstanding Government Code Section 84505, if a top contributor is a committee,
               the top three (3) contributors to that contributing committee must also be disclosed.
               If any disclosed contributor is a committee, the top three (3) contributors who contributed
               two thousand five hundred dollars ($2,500.00) to that contributing committee must
               also be disclosed.</p>
        <p>c.</p>
        <p>Documentation. The following items shall be submitted to the city clerk the same day the required
               Fair Political Practices Commission (FPPC) forms in support of the expenditures for
               the advertisement are filed:</p>
        <p>1.</p>
        <p>A copy of the advertisement subject to this section.</p>
        <p>2.</p>
        <p>If the FPPC forms in support of the disclosures listed on the advertisement are not
               FPPC forms filed with the city, identification of those jurisdictions with which the
               forms are filed and a list of forms filed in support of the disclosures.</p>
        <p>3.</p>
        <p>A rebuttable presumption that the advertisement was sent to the printer on the same
               date as the expenditure listed on the FPPC form filed for the advertisement shall
               be applied. This presumption may be overcome by documentation submitted to the city
               clerk that the advertisement was sent to the printer on a different date.</p>
        <p>d.</p>
        <p>Exception. Disclosure of a top contributor is not required pursuant to this division if the
               city is presented with reasonable evidence that there is a probability that disclosure
               of a top contributor would subject the individual to threats, harassment and reprisals.</p>
        <p>(Ord. No. 8.16, § 1, 6/14/16; Ord. No. 6.18, § 3, 4/24/18; Ord. No. 5.22, § 2, 4/26/22; Ord. No. 10.22, § 2, 6/28/22.)</p>
      </content>
    </section>
  </main>
</lawDoc>
